# WOMAN: Raindrops on roses
# And whiskers on kittens
# Bright copper kettles
# And warm woolen mittens
# Brown paper packages
# Tied up with strings
恐惧拉斯维加斯
（Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas）
# These are a few
# Of my favorite things
一个成了禽兽的人
就不会有痛苦了
【场景交代】我们正在巴斯托的某个地方沙漠的边缘
DUKE NARRATING: We were somewhere around Barstow,
on the edge of the desert,
当药物起作用时...
when the drugs
began to take hold.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING
ON CAR STEREO)
当药物起作用时...
-我记得有这样的一种说法
l remember saying
something like...
I feel a bit lightheaded.
我有点头晕
还是你来开车吧
(EXCLAIMING)
Maybe you should drive.
(BATS SCREECHING)
DUKE NARRATING: SuddenIy
there was a terrible roar
all around us.
突然，
我们周围有很恐怖的叫声…
And the sky was full of
what looked like huge bats.
铺天盖地的来了
一群像蝙蝠的东西…
All swooping and screeching
and diving around the car.
追着我们的车叫
And a voice was screaming...
-它们尖声叫着
-老天，这是些什么鬼东西？
Holy Jesus! What are
these goddamn animals?
(GRUNTING)
(SINGING) Come on, baby
You say something?
Hmm?
你刚才说什么
Never mind.
没什么
It's your turn to drive.
轮到你开车了
DUKE NARRATING: No point
in mentioning these bats,
l thought.
我想，
没必要再提蝙蝠的事了
The poor bastard'll
see them soon enough.
那个家伙
很快就会看见它们的
(SINGING) Baby,
l'm starting to feel human
Ohh, ohh, yeah
Hey, hey, feel with me, baby
'Cause l feel it coming on
Fucking pigs! Flying !
贪吃的家伙，给我滚
All right, let's see.
We had 2 bags of grass,
75 pellets of mescaline,
我们有许多大麻…
一些霉斯卡灵…
5 sheets of
high-powered blotter acid,
五瓶强效迷幻剂…
a salt shaker
half full of cocaine,
一个盐瓶
装了半瓶可卡因…
a whole galaxy of
multicolored uppers, downers,
screamers, laughers.
各种各样的东西，兴奋剂，
好听的故事以及笑话
Also, a quart of tequila,
a quart of rum,
当然还有一夸脱蒸馏酒
和浪姆酒，一瓶啤酒…
a case of beer,
a pint of raw ether...
-一品脱纯酒…
-妈的
Shit!
2 dozen amyls.
两打戊基
Not that we needed
all that for the trip,
这次旅程中，我们并不
需要所有这些东西…
but once you get locked
into a serious
drug collection,
只是一旦你爱上
了收集药品…
the tendency is to
push it as far as you can.
就会无法自拔
The only thing
that really worried me
was the ether.
我唯一担心的是
那份情感催化剂
There is nothing
in the world more helpless
只要对这个东西上了隐…
and irresponsible
and depraved
than a man in the depths
of an ether binge,
那么这个世上恐怕就没有
第二样东西能让你更绝望
and l knew
we'd get into that
rotten stuff pretty soon.
我知道我们就快要
被这个东西给迷住了
WOMAN ON RADIO: A House
subcommittee report says,
根据议院组委会的报道
说在去年…
illegal drugs killed
1 60 American Gls last year,
有160名美国兵死于吸毒…
40 of them in Vietnam.
其中有40名死在越南
Drugs...
(SINGING)
One toke over the line
Sweet Jesus
One toke, man !
One toke over the line!
Sitting downtown
at a railway station
One toke over the line!
One toke, you poor fool?
-吸大麻的家伙，
你这条可怜虫？
Sweet, sweet Mary!
Wait'll you see those
goddamned bats, man.
等着瞧吧
你就会看见那群蝙蝠了
Mine!
One toke over the line
Let's give that boy a lift.
-我们让那个男孩搭个便车
-什么？不！
What? No!
等等！
Wait! We can't stop here.
我们不能在这儿逗留
这可是个蝙蝠城
This is bat country.
Hot damn ! I never rode
in a convertible before!
帅呆了！
我第一次乘坐敞篷车！
Is that right? Well, I guess
you're about ready then,
aren't you?
是吗？那么我想，
你身上应该带了现款吧？
We're your friends.
我们是你的朋友
不会收你的费的，上来吧
We're not like the others,
man. Really.
No more of that talk
or I'll put the fucking
leeches on you. Understand?
你给我闭嘴
不然有你好看的.明白吗？
(GONZO GIGGLING)
Get in.
上来吧
DUKE NARRATING: How Iong
could we maintain, l wondered.
我在想
我们还能坚持多久呢？
How long before
one of us starts raving
and jabbering at this boy?
我们还能坚持多久
不在这个男孩面前胡言乱语？
What will he think then?
到那时不知他会如何想？
This same lonely desert
was the last known home
of the Manson family.
这片同样人迹罕至的沙漠
据说是曼森家族的最后居住所
Would he make
that grim connection
他会报警吗…
when my attorney starts
screaming about bats
and huge manta rays
coming down on the car?
当我的律师被那些从天而降的
蝙蝠吓得尖叫时？
lf so, well, we'll just
have to cut his head off
and bury him somewhere.
如果真这样的话，我们就会
砍掉他的脑袋，把他埋在一个
没人找得到的地方
'Cause it goes without saying
that we can't turn him loose.
不用说，我们是不能放过他的
He'd report us at once
否则他会马上给内地的
某法律事务所打电话…
to some kind of outback
Nazi law enforcement agency
and they'll run us down
like dogs.
他们就会像狗一样地
追着我们不放
Jesus, did l say that,
or just think it?
-老天，我说，还是在想？
-我说出来了吗？
Was l talking?
Did they hear me?
我说出来了吗？
他们听到我说什么了吗？
It's okay.
你也来吸一口吧
Just admiring
the shape of your skull.
BOY: No, thanks!
Maybe l'd better have a chat
with this boy, l thought.
I have asthma!
-不用了，谢谢你！
-我想我最好跟那个男孩谈一下
Perhaps if l explain things,
he'll rest easy.
-我有哮喘！
-也许我的解释会让他放松一些
All right, listen.
好的，听着
There's one thing you should
probably understand.
有件事，你得听明白了
你听得到我说话吗？
Can you hear me?
Good.
很好
(EXCLAIMS)
I want you to have
all the background.
我必须跟你说清楚
This is a very
ominous assignment
这是份苦差事…
with overtones
of extreme personal danger.
需要冒很大的险
I'm a Doctor of Journalism,
man.
我是一名新闻学博士
这很重要，妈的！
This is important,
goddamn it!
This is a fucking true story!
这可是真的
Shit! Hey, what're you doing?
Sit down. Get the fuck. . .
他妈的-
Get your hands
off my fucking head !
不要扯我的头发
Now, now, now.
-冷静，冷静
-我们没法心灵相通
但这是为什么呢？
DUKE NARRATING: Our vibrations
were getting nasty, but why?
Was there no communication
in this car?
难道这辆车上的人
没有交际能力？
Had we deteriorated
to the level of dumb beasts?
我们不可能退化到
跟兽类一样了吧？
I want you to understand
that this man at the wheel
is my attorney.
开车的那个是我的律师
He's not just some dingbat
I found on the Strip, man.
他可不是我随随便便
从斯德帕那个地方找来的傻子
他是个外地人
He's a foreigner.
I think he's probably Samoan.
我猜他应该是萨摩亚人吧
这个可没什么关系，是吧？
It doesn't matter,
though, does it?
Are you prejudiced?
-你有种族偏见吗？
-不，不，没有
Hell, no.
I didn't think so.
我想不是吧
Because in spite of his race,
this man is extremely valuable
to me.
除了他的血缘关系以外
对我来说，他还是非常重要的
Oh, shit.
I forgot about the beer.
You want some?
-妈的.我忘了我还拿着啤酒
你要来一点吗？-不用了
No.
How about some ether?
-那要来点感情催化剂吗？
-什么？
What?
Never mind.
All right, let's get right
to the heart of this thing.
好了，没什么
我们现在切入正题吧
-二十四小时前
我们还坐在…
我们在贝弗莉.海特旅馆的…
24 hours ago
we were sitting. . .
DUKE NARRATING:
...in the Pogo Lounge
of the Beverly Heights Hotel.
波罗厅里，
我们坐在天井区，当然了…
ln the patio section,
of course.
Drinking Singapore Slings
with mescal on the side.
喝着新加坡斯林酒
以及麦斯卡酒…
Hiding from
the brutish realities of
this foul year of our Lord,
想逃出这个充满肉欲的现实
这个污秽的救世主年代，1971年
1 971 .
那群愚蠢的警察-
Cops were going apeshit. . .
(MUTTERING)
Perhaps this is the call
you've been waiting
for all this time, sir.
先生，这个也许
是你一直在等的电话吧
Perhaps.
也许吧
Yeah?
是我
Mmm-hmm.
Mmm. Really?
All right. Yeah?
真的吗，很好
是吗？是的，是
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Oh, yeah. Okay. Bye.
好，再见
That was headquarters.
They want me to. . .
上面的人，他们希望我-
(CLEARS THROAT)
(COINS CLATTERING)
(WHISPERING) Thank you.
谢谢你
They want me to go
to Las Vegas at once.
他们希望
我马上去趟拉斯维加斯…
Make contact with
a Portuguese photographer
named Lacerda.
找一个叫拉喀达的
葡萄牙摄影师
He'll have all the details.
他会把详细情况给我们说的
All I have to do
is check into my
soundproof suite.
我只需要去找到隔音套房
他自然会找到我的
He'll seek me out.
What do you think?
-你认为如何？
-看来会有不少麻烦
Sounds like real trouble.
You're gonna need
plenty of legal advice
before this thing is over.
要解决这件事，
我们需要一些法律意见
Oh, yeah.
说的对
As your attorney,
I advise you
作为你的律师，我建议你
去租一辆高速的无顶蓬的车
to rent a very fast car
with no top.
And you'll need the cocaine.
你要带上可卡因
Tape recorder
for special music.
以及放美妙音乐的录音机
Acapulco shirts.
阿卡普尔科衬衣
Get the hell out of L.A.
for at least 48 hours.
因为从洛杉机到
那至少48个小时的路程
Blows my weekend.
Why?
-我的周末又泡汤了
-你在说什么？
'Cause, naturally,
I'm gonna have
to go with you.
'因为，很显然地
我必须陪你一起去
And we're gonna have to
arm ourselves to the teeth.
我们得全幅武装自己
Well, why not?
好吧，就这样了吧
I mean,
if a thing's worth doing,
it's worth doing right.
我的意思就是说，既然一件事
值得去做就该把它做好
This is the American Dream
in action.
这是一次寻找美国梦的机会
Wait!
等等
Shit, we'd be fools not to
ride this strange torpedo
all the way out to the end.
真是笨，我们真该乘
这奇怪的鱼舰直接到终点
Indeed. We must do it.
不错，我们该这样做
What kind of story
is this?
这次的主题是什么？
It's the Mint 400.
是Mint400
The richest off-road race
for motorcycles
and dune buggies
这是一次空前的
由摩托车和沙丘车组成的越野赛
in the history
of organized sport.
It's a fantastic spectacle
in honor of some
fatback grosero,
场面惊人的壮观…
是一个叫格洛的大胖子
投资办成的…
who owns
the luxurious Mint Hotel
in downtown Las Vegas.
在拉斯维加斯市区他拥有
那个豪华的薄菏饭店
At least that's what
the press release says,
anyway.
这些都是新闻界透露的
Well, as your attorney,
I advise you to buy
a motorcycle.
作为你的律师
我建议你去买辆摩托车
How else can you cover
a thing like this righteously?
像这种事，你还能用什么
更忠实的方式报道呢？
Well, we're gonna have to
drum it up on our own.
好吧，我们自己去干吧
Pure Gonzo journalism.
纯粹是你的新闻报道
Shit!
见鬼
(TIRES SQUEALING)
DUKE NARRATING: Getting
hold of the drugs and shirts
had been no problem.
找药跟衬衣倒不成问题…
But the car and tape recorder
were not easy things
to round up
但是要想在好莱坞
星期五下午的6.：30之前…
at 6:30 on a Friday afternoon
in Hollywood.
搞到车和录音机
可不是件容易的事
Sounds beautiful.
想法不错
很好，不要挂
Great. Hang on to it.
他妈的A，
那位绅士有张主要的信用卡！
Fucking A,
the gentleman has
a major credit card !
That's right, man.
Don't take any guff
from these fucking swine.
好的，伙计.
不要再跟那头猪废话了
I just got through
saying that.
好吧，我不想再跟你多说了
Do you realize
who the fuck
you're talking to?
你知不知道自己是在跟谁讲话？
Right.
Do you?
Be over in 30 minutes.
三十分钟内马上解决
DUKE: We're gonna
need a sound store.
我们必须找家可靠的商店
GONZO: We won't
make the nut unless
we have unlimited credit.
-没有信用卡，我们做不成交易
-我们会做成的，伙计
DUKE: Jesus Christ.
We will, man.
You Samoans
are all the same.
你们这些萨摩亚人
怎么都这样
You have no faith
in the essential decency
of the white man's culture.
你们总是不相信
纯种白人的文化
DUKE NARRATING:
The store was closed.
那家商店关门了…
But the salesman said
he could wait if we hurry.
但是售货员说着急的话
他可以等着我们
(SIRENS WAILING)
But we were
delayed en route
when a Stingray in front of us
killed a pedestrian.
但在途中我们遇到一起车祸
所以去晚了
We had trouble again
with the car rental agency.
我们又跟租车商
发生了点冲突
Hey, Mr. Duke,
we're all settled.
杜克先生，我们准备好了
您只要在签个名就可以了
If I could just
get your John Hancock,
you're on your way.
Yeah.
-好的
-请您一定要好好爱惜这辆车
Listen,
you're gonna be real
careful with this car, right?
Oh, yeah, man. Of course.
这还用说吗，我一定会的
Good. Jeez. . .
No, no, no!
(PANTING)
好快的速度
Holy smokes!
You just backed over
a two-foot concrete abutment,
你倒车时也该减减速
you didn't even slow down.
What were you going about,
I don't know,
45 miles an hour backwards?
你知不知道自己刚才在做什么
45英里/时的速度倒车？
Hey.
There's no harm done.
-没什么关系的，
那么紧张做什么-什么？
Oh?
I always test
the transmission that way,
我对这个很有经验
这是为了减轻车后部的压力
the rear end
for stress factors.
Boy, this is really
a nice pen, man.
-伙计，这支笔可真不赖啊
-听着，你-
Hey, listen, you. . .
You fellows haven't
been drinking, have you?
你们这些家伙
是不是从没开过车？
No. Not me.
Oh.
-我可不是
-那么-
We're responsible people.
Hey, hey, hey!
我们是有责任心的人
Goddamn it,
you've got my pen !
见鬼，你拿了我的笔
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Goddamn hippies!
妈的嬉皮士！
DUKE NARRATING: We spent
the rest of that night
那个晚上我们就把剩余时间
用来采购物品包装我们的车
rounding up materials
and packing the car.
Then we ate some mescaline
and went swimming.
我们吃了些致幻剂后
就去游泳了
Our trip was different.
我们的旅程有些与众不同
lt was to be
a classic affirmation
这是一次特别的任务…
of everything right and true
in the national character.
这是一次去调查
整个民族的风格的机会…
A gross physical salute
to the fantastic possibilities
of life in this country.
是这个国家最壮观的一次
身体与灵魂相结和的体验
But only for those
with true grit.
但这可只对那些
真正的英雄行得通
And we are chock
full of that, man.
而我们就是这样的人
Damn right!
完全正确
My attorney
understands this concept,
despite his racial handicap.
虽说我的律师不是个白人
但他能理解这一点
But do you?
你能吗？
(GIGGLING)
He said he understood,
but l could see in his eyes
that he didn't.
他说他懂了，但我从他的眼神
可以看出他是在撒谎
He was lying to me.
他在说谎
(GONZO SCREAMING)
药
Medicine!
What?
-什么？
-药
Medicine?
Oh, yeah, medicine. Right.
药？好的，药！
就在这儿
Right here.
(SHRIEKING)
Don't worry.
This man has a bad heart.
不用担心，这个家伙心脏不好
Angina pectoris.
心绞痛
But we have a cure for it.
Here you go.
但我们有医治它的办法
含着，好的
All right.
Big whiff. Big whiff.
Big whiff, sonny boy.
深深地吸一口气.吸气
吸气，好的，乖孩子
There you go. Much better.
好了，好多了
Now for the doctor.
现在轮到医生了
(GROANING)
(SQUEALING)
What the. . .
我们-
What the fuck
are we doing out here
in the middle of the desert?
我们在这荒无的沙漠中干嘛呢？
Somebody call the police.
We need help.
谁给警察打个电话
我们需要帮助
We need help.
We need help. We need help.
我们需要帮助
(HORN HONKS)
(LAUGHING)
The truth.
真话
Truth?
真话？
Now, we're going to Vegas. . .
我们要去的地方是维加斯…
Vegas.
To croak a scag baron
named Savage Henry.
去杀一个叫萨维奇.亨利的人
It's true.
Why? Because I've
known him for years
but he ripped us off.
-这是真的-为什么呢？
因为他出卖了我们…
出卖了他的老朋友们
DUKE: And you know
what that means.
-你知道这意味着什么吗
-你知道这意味着什么
And you know what that means.
Right?
No.
-对吗？
-不，我不知道
Savage Henry
has cashed his check.
萨维奇.亨利…
Cashed his check.
把他的支票兑换成现款了
-把支票兑换成现款了
-我们要掏出他的心肺
And we're gonna
rip his lungs out.
然后生吃了它们
那个杂种别想逃过这一劫
That bastard won't
get away with this.
I mean, what is
going on in this country
when a scum sucker like that
如果像那样的人渣不能被
像我这样的新闻博士铲除的话…
can get away
with sandbagging
a Doctor of Journalism?
那这个国家还有何公理可言
Can you tell me that?
Hey!
Thanks for the ride!
I like you guys!
-嘿！-谢谢你们的便车！
我喜欢你们！
Really, don't worry about me!
Wait a minute!
-真的，不用担心我！
-等一等
Come back and have a beer!
回来喝一杯吧
Shit. Fuck.
见鬼
I'm gonna miss him.
妈的，我会想念他的
-让开！
-你看见他的眼神了吗？
Move over.
Did you see his eyes?
We have to get
out of California
before that kid finds a cop.
要尽开离开这
那个家伙想告我们
(CACKLING)
Come on.
Scoot over, you fat bastard.
往旁边靠一点，你这个胖仔
We had a real freak
on our hands!
-看来我们真是很怪诞的人！
-该死
Oh, shit.
DUKE NARRATING: It was
absolutely imperative that
we get to the Mint Hotel
新闻部的人已经说过了…
before the deadline
for press registration.
如果不是按时赶到薄荷饭店
Otherwise we might
have to pay for our suite.
那我们就得自己掏腰包付费
(SCREECHING)
Jesus!
天！你看上帝对我们
都做了些什么，老兄？
Did you see what God
just did to us, man?
不关上帝的事，
那是你自找的
God didn't do that.
You did it.
You're a fucking
narcotics agent.
I knew it.
我知道你是个毒品代售商
That was our cocaine,
you pig !
那是我们俩的，你这头猪！
你这头该死的猪，卑鄙下流的家伙！
You fucking pig, swine, whore!
You better be careful.
你最好小心点
Plenty of vultures out here
that'll pick your bones
clean before morning.
这附近到处都是秃鹰
天亮前保证让你尸肉全无
You fucking whore.
你这个下贱货
(FEIGNING LAUGHTER)
Here's your half
of the sunshine acid. Eat it.
这一半迷幻药给你，吃吧
Yeah.
好的
Great.
棒极了
How long do I have?
我还有多长的时间？
As your attorney,
I advise you to drive
at top speed
作为你的律师，
我奉劝你开到最大马力
or it'll be a goddamn
miracle if we can get there
如果在你变成野兽前赶到饭店
那简直是个天大的奇迹
before you turn
into a wild animal.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUTTERING)
(SINGING) Yeah, yeah
你做好准备了吗？
Are you ready for that?
Checking into a Vegas hotel
under a phony name
你吸了毒…
with intent to
commit capital fraud
and a head full of acid?
最好准备用假名字登记住入饭店？
I sure hope so.
我也希望如此
DUKE NARRATING: 30 minutes.
三十分钟，快要到了
lt was going to be very close.
不要在内华达州赌博
(SINGING) WeII,
she's all you'd ever want
She's the kind
l'd like to flaunt
And take to dinner
MAN ON P.A. : WeIcome
to the Mint Hotel!
欢迎来到薄荷饭店
(SINGING) WeII,
she always knows her place
She's got style
She's got grace
She's a winner
(HORN HONKING)
She's a lady
Whoa, whoa, whoa
Hmm? Mmm.
(SINGING) TaIking about
my little lady
MAN: Come on, take the ticket.
We're busy here.
来，拿着这张入场券
我们这儿业务非常繁忙
(SINGING) And the Iady is mine
Come on, take the ticket.
Take it.
快点，拿着啊，拿着
Take the ticket.
把入场券拿着
我需要这个，是吗？
I need this, right?
I'll remember your face.
我会记住你的
DUKE NARRATING: There is
no way of explaining
the terror l felt.
没有语言能
形容得出我的那种恐惧
WOMAN ON P.A. : Attention,
all Mint Hotel guests.
请大家注意了，各位来宾
Will the owner
of a green Pinto
请问是否有位
开着绿色带有花斑…
Minnesota license plate
TG0432...
在明尼苏达州的牌照是TG0432-
DUKE NARRATING:
l was pouring sweat.
我汗如雨下
My blood is too thick
for Nevada.
我还不能适应
内华达州的气候
l've never been able
to properly explain myself
in this climate.
在这种天气下我
根本无法解释清我自己
(MAN CHATTERING)
Okay. Be quiet, be calm.
好的，冷静点，平静下来
这一切是为了名声，
地位和新闻
Name, rank
and press affiliation.
Nothing else.
再无其它
. . .hamburger stand.
She was a waitress
about 1 6 years old.
…在停车场，她是个女服务生，
大约十六岁左右
They chopped her goddamn
head off right there
in the parking lot.
他们在停车场
把她的头砍下来了…
Then they cut all
kinds of holes in her
and sucked out the blood.
在她身上钻了很洞
吸干了她的血
They were after
the pineal gland, I think.
我想应该是在松果腺后吧
Yeah.
No. How's your mama?
-不，你妈妈还好吧？
-不要想着药品
lgnore this terrible drug.
Yeah.
对
Pretend it's not happening.
就当它没发生过
(GRUNTS)
Hi there!
你好
My name?
我的名字？
拉奥尔.杜克
Raoul Duke!
On the list. Freelance.
名单上，自由撰稿人.
名单是这样写的，是吧？
On the list, then?
Total coverage.
来作完全的新闻报道
I have my attorney. . .
我是跟我的律师…
一道来的…
With me.
And I realize that his name
is not on that list.
我知道他的名字
并没写在上面…
But we must have that suite!
但是一定有人
替我们提前预订了房间！
Yes, we must have that suite.
一定有人预定了那间房
What's the score here?
这儿的手续该如何办？
What's next?
接下来该怎么办？
Your suite isn't ready yet.
你的套房还没有准备好…
But someone
was looking for you.
但是有人一直在找你
No! We haven't done
anything yet! Move!
不，我们还没准备好
I can handle this.
我可以处理这件事
This man suffers
from a bad heart.
这个人有很严重的心脏病
But I have
plenty of medicine.
My name is Dr. Gonzo.
不要紧，我准备了很多药
我是贡兹博士
Prepare our suite at once.
We'll be in the bar.
马上替我们安排好房间
我们会在酒吧里
(GRUNTS)
I don't know about you,
but I'm starting
to feel that drink.
我并不认识你
但很感谢你的美酒
(CHUCKLING)
(GROWLS)
Hey, beat it.
Beat it. Go on.
走开，走开，快
Well, I like the way
you did that.
我欣赏你的那种做事方式
(EXCLAIMS)
Come on. Come on. Come on.
来，过来，过来，不要紧
What's that?
Come on, come on.
Let's get some peanuts.
-小心！-来吧，来吧，
我们来看一些漫画吧
DUKE: Peanuts?
That's one thing
that's good for you, man.
这是唯一对你有些帮助的事
漫画
Peanuts, man.
Jesus!
上帝
2 Cuba Libres, beer
and mescal on the side.
-来瓶啤酒外加龙舌兰
-好了，先生
BARTENDER: You got it.
I'll bet you're a Libra.
Mmm.
我敢打赌你是天秤座的
(LAUGHING)
(WOMAN MOANING)
Who's Lacerda?
Lacerda?
谁是拉喀达？他在12楼等我们
Yeah, he's waiting for us
on the 1 2th floor.
Room 1 250. Lacerda.
1250号房.拉喀达
DUKE NARRATING:
l couldn't remember.
我记不起来了
The name rang a bell,
but l couldn't concentrate.
我对这个名字有点印像
但一时却想不起来了
Terrible things were happening
all around us.
我们陷入了绝境
(GURGLING)
Buy us some golf shoes,
要一些高尔夫球鞋…
otherwise we'll never
get out of this place alive.
否则我们不能活着
离开这个地方了
Impossible to walk
in this muck.
要在这种垃圾里走路
简直不可能
No footing at all.
完全没有立足之地
WOMAN ON P.A. :
Mr. Roger Pratt, please
call the hotel operator.
罗杰先生
请给饭店接线员打个电话
(SINGING) How can I bear
to see your heart break?
To see your heart break
Over me
(GROWLING)
l was right in the middle
of a fucking reptile zoo
毫无疑问，我现在是
在一个爬行动物园…
and somebody was giving booze
to these goddamn things.
有人给了这些东西酒喝
lt won't be long now
before they tear us to shreds.
要不了多久，它们就可以
把我们撕个稀巴烂
(MUMBLING INCOHERENTLY)
Please!
拜?
Tell them to get out
their fucking golf shoes!
快告诉我高尔夫球鞋在哪
(ALL GASPING)
Jesus God Almighty,
look at that bunch
over there, man.
万能的主啊，看看那些家伙
They've spotted us.
他们发现我们了
GONZO: That's the press table,
man.
那是报社的时间安排
We're gonna have to sign in
for our credentials.
我们必须去签到
Okay?
怎么样？
Are you ready?
Hmm?
你准备好了吗？
Are you ready?
你准备好了吗
Come on, hurry up.
Wait! Wait, wait!
Fucking don't leave me here!
-走吧，我们快点
-等等，不要丢下我
BOY: Two club sandwiches,
两份古巴三明治…
and 2 more club sandwiches.
另加两份俱乐部三明治…
One, two, three, four
shrimp cocktails.
一，二，三，四杯鸡尾酒…
还有九杯新鲜柚子
Hmm?
And nine fresh grapefruit.
维生素C，
可以补充我们所需营养
GONZO: Vitamin C.
Need all we can get.
BOY: Four chicken. . .
DUKE: There's a big
machine in the sky.
-四只鸡-
-还有…
天空出现一些巨大的飞行器
像是…
Some kind of. . .
Quart of rum.
Well, electric snake
coming straight at us.
-一瓶浪姆酒
-是电蛇直接在向我们开火
GONZO: Shoot it.
把它射下来
Not yet.
I want to study its habits.
等等，我们先看看它的动向
BOY: You motorcycle people
sure are hearty eaters.
你们这些家伙
显然是来吃人心的
I need the cart. I need
to return with the cart.
是手推车
要归还手推车
Thank you, but the cart
needs to go back with. . .
I'll be back!
谢谢，但手推车必须送回
我一会再回来
GONZO: You bastard.
I've been hit, man !
-你这个王八蛋
-我手烧伤了
I leave you alone
for three minutes
我只不过一会儿没管你
你就被那些东西…
and you start
waving that goddamn
marlin spike around
yelling about reptiles.
吓得屁滚尿流
What're you talking about,
man?
-你在胡说八道些什么？
-你怕那些人
You scared the shit
out of those people.
They were ready
to call the cops.
他们会叫警察的
Yes, sir, you were lucky
I came back in time.
-你该庆幸我及时回来了
-不要靠近我
Don't come near me.
Don't come fucking near me!
不要管我
Leave me alone.
Hell, the only reason
they gave us press passes
他们这所以这样做
唯一的原因就是想赶你出去
was to get you
out of there, man.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Oh, God ! What's that?
天，那是什么东西？
That scene straightened me
right out, man.
你这幅德性真让我恶心
Who's at the door?
有人在敲门
MAN ON T.V. : As the bombing
continues in Laos...
-战争在老挝国进行的同时-
-等等
Just a minute.
妈的
Holy shit. Oh, my God.
我的上帝
(MAN CONTINUES
CHATTERING ON T.V.)
Hi. I'm Lacerda,
your photographer.
嗨，我是拉喀达
你们的摄影师
杜克？
Duke?
DUKE: Mmm-hmm.
在那后边
Back there.
Duke?
-北越看起来似乎想-
-杜克？杜克？
Duke? Hi !
嗨
(LAUGHS)
Lacerda. Your photographer.
拉喀达，你们的摄影师
You're not Portuguese, man !
你不是葡萄牙人，老兄
Hey, too bad you guys
missed the bikes checking in.
真可怜，你们错过了
这场比赛的开幕式
Oh, man, what a sight!
啊，那可真壮观
Husquavarnas, Yamahas, DMZs.
-越野摩托，亚马哈车，DMZs车
Kawasakis!
川畸车
Maicos. Pursang !
-麦克斯车.帕甚车
Swedish Fireballs.
雅典燃烧弹
Couple of Triumphs.
Here and there a CZ.
两辆胜利牌车
到处都是CZ车
All very, very fast.
它们都非常快
Very.
非常非常快
What a race it's gonna be.
这将是一场无比精彩的比赛
是的
Yeah.
I'm gonna let myself out.
我自己出去
We know what
you're up to, man.
Hmm?
我们知道你想做什么，伙计
I'm gonna tell you. . .
我要告诉你-
He's lying to us.
I could see it in his eyes.
他在撒谎
我从他的眼神中看出这点
Eyes?
眼神？
MAN ON T.V. : Late
battle reports indicate...
-最近从战场发回的报道显示-
Panic now, Charlie.
Turn this shit off.
关掉这鬼东西
DUKE NARRATING: The racers
were ready at dawn.
比赛一大早就开始了
Very tense.
非常激烈
ln some circles, the Mint 400
is a far, far better thing
than the Super Bowl,
从某种程度上说Mint400
远比…
超级杯，
肯塔基赛马会…
the Kentucky Derby
and the Lower Oakland
Roller Derby Finals
all rolled into one.
奥克兰赛马会总决赛要强得多
Hey! Slow down !
This is a restricted area!
停下！
这里不能随便出入！
This race attracts
a very special breed.
这场比赛吸引了
各方各面的人来看
Fuck off.
All right.
-滚开
-好的
lt was time to get grounded,
现在该四周转转
了解这里的情况…
to ponder this
rotten assignment
and figure out
how to cope with it.
考虑一下如何
来做这份工作了
lt was time to do the job.
要开始工作了
Those of us
who had been up all night
像我们这种彻夜不眠的人
早餐不需咖啡和油炸饼
were in no mood
for coffee and donuts.
We wanted strong drink.
我们需要的是一些烈酒
We were, after all
毕竟，我们是…
the absolute cream
of the national
sporting press.
是来做体育报道的
MAN: Pull !
拉，放！
We were gathered here
in Las Vegas
我们从四面八方聚到一起来
为的就是见证体育史上
这一历史时刻
for this very
special moment in sport.
When it comes to
a thing like this,
they don't fool around.
一旦开始工作
我们就会谨慎认真
(SNORING)
It's just beautiful.
这真是太美了
Money plays. Money plays.
来，赌一把啦，赌一把
Kill the body,
the head will die.
人死了，大脑也就会死了
阿里-弗雷泽的比赛
Ali-Frazier fight.
Crazy shit, man.
-疯子
-60年代末的一场好戏
A proper end to the '60s.
Ali beaten by
a human hamburger.
阿里输了
Both Kennedys
murdered by mutants.
-两个肯尼迪都是被人杀死的
-比赛开始了
MAN: Hey, they're starting !
Oh, shit, they're starting.
Let's go!
好的，开始了，我们走
MAN ON P.A. :
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士们，先生们…
welcome to the start
of the $50,000 Mint 400
Desert Race.
欢迎来参加我们的五万元
Mint400沙漠越野比赛…
With a purse of $50,000
going to the winner
本赛获胜者可得五万元…
of this grueling,
gut-wrenching, dust-eating,
这是一场挑战人体极限
勇气的考验…
in-your-face
motocross extravaganza!
一场你们最喜欢的摩托车越野赛！
And away we go!
他们开始了！
We've got
rooster tails going!
我们的勇士们出发了！
我们在这儿为他们加油吧！
We're here to spit
in your enemy's eye!
There they go.
比赛开始了
好的，我们的第二组十个
参赛队员也已经做好准备了
All right, our second group
of 1 0 is getting in place.
Kawasakis, Triumphs, Maicos.
川崎车，胜利车，梅科斯车
Here we are.
We're ready to go.
好，准备
绿旗，出发
lt's the green flag,
and they're off!
Another great start
with a lot of dirt
happening on this hill!
好，第二队狂狮出发了！
All right, here we go
with the third group.
现在是第三队，
他们要出发了
And they're off!
Here we go.
Number 45 riding in
the number 4 position
在第四起跑线的45号…
is choking as the dust flies!
好像被灰尘窒息了！
You'd better wet those
bandannas you got
stretched over your face!
各位，大家最好是把手帕
打湿了围在脸上！
DUKE NARRATING: There was
something like 1 90 more bikes
waiting to start.
好像还有190多辆车等着出发
Give me a beer, man.
They were due to go off,
1 0 at a time
-伙计，来杯啤酒
-他们一组十个人…
every two minutes.
每隔两分钟走一组
BARTENDER: There you go,
buddy.
你的
(BLOWING NOSE)
Goddamn it.
What day is it? Saturday?
Shit.
-妈的，今天星期几？
星期六？
-妈的
More like Sunday.
玩像是星期天
Hello! Anyone?
喂，有人吗？
Have you seen the race?
比赛进程如何了？
DUKE NARRATING: By 10:00,
they were spread out
all over the course.
到10.：00比赛进入白热化状态
lt was no longer a race.
这已经不是一场比赛了
Now it was
an endurance contest.
现在它简直就是
一场考验耐力的比赛
The idea of trying
to cover this race
想来报道这场比赛的念头
真的是太荒谬了
in any conventional
press sense was absurd.
Hey! It's pretty great, huh?
What?
-嘿，这真是太精彩了？
-什么？
Come on in !
上车
(SHUTTER CLICKING)
I'm just gonna try
different combinations
of lenses and film
我要试着用不同的透镜和胶卷…
until I find something
that works in this dust!
以便在这种尘条件下摄影！
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
What the hell?
那是什么东西？
(GUNS FIRING)
That's fucking
machine guns, man.
They're firing at us.
那是机枪
它们正朝着我们，机枪！
Machine guns.
It's a goddamn war zone!
这是交战地带！
马上带我们离开这儿！
Get us out of here quick!
(LACERDA WHOOPING)
Quick, man !
快点，伙计们！我们会没命的
We're gonna be killed,
for fuck's sake!
What the. . .
Oh, no. Oh, God. Oh, God.
那是-噢，不
上帝，上帝
Oh, God.
Where's the damn race?
比赛区在哪？
Beats me, man.
我不知道
We're just good,
patriotic Americans
like yourself.
我们都是有爱国心的美国人
你们是一样的
What outfit you fellows with?
你们用的是什么装配？
Oh. The sporting press.
We're friendlies.
我们是在做体育报道节目
我们是友善的，没有恶意
租来的人
Hired geeks.
我说的是实话
Yeah.
我们走
Let's go.
(LACERDA WHOOPING)
Good luck, gentlemen.
祝你们好运，先生们
Get him !
-抓住他！
-怪人
Freaks.
Take me back to the pits.
-带我回到修理站去
-不，不，不行，我们必须继续前进
No! No, no, no.
We have to go on.
We need total coverage!
我们要做全面的报道
DUKE NARRATING:
lt was time, l felt,
我想，是时候对这件事
作一次全面的认真的分析了
for an agonizing reappraisal
of the whole scene.
You're fired.
你被解雇了
Awful jackass.
你这个傻子
All right.
好的
Just drive into the dust!
-不是，开到灰尘中去！
-我再也不想见到你了
I never wanna see you again.
Just drive into the dust!
开到尘土中去
Huh?
Oh !
The race was
definitely underway.
很显然的，比赛还在进行中
l had witnessed the start.
我目睹了它的开始
这是肯定的
l was sure of that much.
But what now?
但现在呢，情况如何了？
What comes next?
接下来会是什么呢？
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
Put on the radio.
把收音机打开
打开
Turn on the tape machine.
Roll every
goddamn window down.
把窗户摇下去
Let us taste this
cool desert wind.
我们吹吹这沙漠里凉爽的风
Ah, yes.
This is what it's all about.
是的，事情也就是这样了
DUKE NARRATING:
Total control now.
现在一切都在控制中了…
Tooling along the main drag
on a Saturday night in Vegas.
维加斯一个星期六的晚上
在这样的一条路上
Two good old boys
in a fire-apple
red convertible.
有两个人
他们在一辆红似苹果的敞蓬车里…
Stoned, ripped...
有些醉意，有些飘飘然，
也有些痛苦
Twisted, good people.
好家伙
Hot fuck.
That sounds heavy.
妈的.
听起好吓人
29 cent hot dogs.
29分的热狗
What are we doing here?
我们来这儿是做什么的？
Are we here to
entertain ourselves
or do the job?
是娱乐呢
还是来工作的？
Do the job, of course.
当然是工作了
Here we go.
Crab Louie and
a quart of muscatel for $20.
好吧.我们去吃路易蟹，
喝点麝香葡萄酒价值20元
作为你的律师
我建议你去热带天堂酒店…
As your attorney,
I advise you to drive
over to the Tropicana.
Guy Lombardo.
He's in the Blue Room
with his Royal Canadians.
跟盖.伦巴多多多联系
他跟他的皇室加拿大人在蓝房间
Why?
-为什么？
-为什么？什么为什么？
Why? Why what?
Why should I pay
my hard-earned dollars
to watch a fucking corpse?
我干嘛要用我辛苦钱
去看一具尸体？
I don't know about you,
我真不懂你…
but in my line of business
it's important to be hep.
-但在我的生意经里
被人了解是很重要的
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
你知不知道你在做什么？
This is not a parking area!
You've got to move your car!
这里不可以停车！
快把你们的车开走！
You can't park your car here.
Excuse me. Sir!
-你们不可以把车停在这里
-对不起，先生！
What?
-什么？
-你不能把-
You can't park. . . Hey!
You can't park your car here!
你们不能把车停在这里！
Why not?
为什么不能？
这个地方停车是很理想的
Is this not
a reasonable place to park?
Reasonable?
You're on a sidewalk!
很理想？
你们把车停在人行道上！
这里是人行道！
It's a sidewalk!
This is not a parking area!
Debbie Reynolds?
-不是停车的地方！
-黛比.雷诺兹？
You can't park
on the sidewalk!
-你们不能停在人行道上！
-场面很火爆
Seems like a hot ticket.
Excuse me, sir?
Drove all the way from L.A.
for this show.
我们专程从洛杉矶
赶来看这场表演
我们是黛比的朋友
We're friends of Debbie's.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
Okay, bye.
We'll see you later.
-好的，再见
-一会再
DUKE NARRATING: This was
Bob Hope's turf,
-这是鲍勃.霍普的
(SINGING)
Strangers in the night
Frank Sinatra's,
Spiro Agnew's.
弗兰克.希纳特拉的
(SINGING) Exchanging gIances
斯皮罗.阿格纽的地盘
The place fairly reeked
of high-grade Formica
and plastic palm trees.
这个地方到处都是高级的
丽光板和塑料棕o树
Clearly a high-class
refuge for big spenders.
很显然，是那些上流社会的人物
来挥金如土的地方
It's started.
Is she on stage?
-节目开始了，她会登台演出吗？
-会的，票都买完了
MAN: She is. Sold out.
Sorry, sir.
Full house. I'm sorry, sir.
对不起啦，先生，满堂红
不好意思啦，先生
We drove all the way
from L.A. for this show.
我们是特意从洛杉矶
赶来看这场演出的
I said there are
no seats left, sir,
at any price.
-我已经说过了，没有座位了
-他妈的座位
Fuck seats!
We're friends with Debbie.
-我们跟黛比是朋友
我们还作过爱
I used to romp with her.
Are you prepared
to go to court?
-你想在法庭上见面？
-那可不一定
Well, that depends.
I wanna talk to you
for a second.
来，我们聊聊
Your attitude constitutes
a breach of faith.
-你的态度有些过火
-嗨
In Nevada, that's illegal.
在内华达州，
这样说是违法的
What's your name?
-你叫什么？
-我的名字？托尼.皮扎卡特
My name? Tony Pizzacata.
GONZO: Tony Pizzacata.
托尼.皮扎卡特
TONY: What, may I ask,
is your name, sir?
请问您尊姓大名？
GONZO: It's on my
driver's license.
我的驾驶证上有
I think we might be able
to squeeze you in, sir.
我们也许可以让你进去，先生
Thank you kindly.
-谢谢你的关照
-你们必须站在后面
You'll have to
stand in the back.
After a lot of bad noise
he let us in for nothing
一阵噪音过后
他就让我们进去了…
provided
we would stand quietly
in the back and not smoke.
只是让我们不要大声嚷嚷，
不要吸烟
Excellent.
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士们，先生们…
the Desert lnn
is proud to present
the one, the only,
沙漠饭店很荣幸地邀请到了
这位独一无二的…
the incomparable
Miss Debbie Reynolds!
无与伦比的
黛比.雷诺兹小姐！
(CHORUS SINGING)
Ooh, ooh
DEBBIE: Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen!
晚上好，各位！
lt's wonderful to be here
with all you fabulous people!
能跟你们一起度过今夜
我真是太高兴了！
Let's rock and roll!
好吧，让我们大家
一起来跳摇摆舞吧
(CHORUS SINGING)
Sgt. Pepper's
Lonely Hearts Club Band
Hey!
What the hell's going on?
出什么事了？
Get them out!
-让他们出去！
-快点，出去
Come on, get out of here!
Get them out.
让他们出去
Out!
出去，让他们走
(DUKE GIGGLING HYSTERICALLY)
Shit! We wandered into
a fucking time capsule there.
妈的！我们来的可真不是时候
卑鄙的家伙！
Scumbag !
I'll find where you live
and burn your house down,
you piece of shit!
你们这群王八蛋
我要把你们的房子烧个精光！
What happened?
Oh.
出什么事了？
One of these days I'll toss
a fucking bomb in that place.
他妈的，看着吧
总有一天我要在那投颗炸弹
(MUSIC PLAYING)
好的，看到了吗？
Oh, wait. You see that?
This is the place, man.
就是这个地方，看到了吗
They'll never
fuck with us here.
他们可不会再把我们赶出来了
Where's the ether?
Mescaline's not working.
情感催化剂在哪？
霉斯卡灵已经起不了作用了
Oh.
There we go. Right.
就这样吧
Yeah. Why not?
是的，为什么不可以呢？
Yeah.
是的
(SNIFFING)
(GROANS)
这恶魔催化剂
DUKE NARRATING: DeviI ether.
lt makes you behave
like the village drunkard
in some early lrish novel.
它能让你像爱尔兰
早期小说里的乡下醉汉
Total loss of all
basic motor skills.
让你完全不知道
该如何开摩托车
Blurred vision,
no balance, numb tongue.
视力模糊
没有平衡度，舌头僵硬
The mind recoils in horror,
意识力已起不到作用…
unable to communicate
with the spinal column,
无法跟你的脊柱配合，
走路直不起腰…
which is interesting
because you can
actually watch yourself
有趣的是，你知道
自己的这种可怕的行为…
behaving in this terrible way
but you can't control it.
但是你却无法控制
You approach the turnstiles
and know that
when you get there
你正朝十字转门走去
而且知道到达时你要做些什么…
you have to give the man $2
or he won't let you inside.
给那个看门的两美元
否则他不会让你进去…
But when you get there
everything goes wrong.
但等你到了那儿的时候
却发生了一点意外
Some angry Rotarian
shoves you
一些愤怒的扶轮社的会员推着你
你在想“这里出什么事了？'”
and you think,
"What's happening here?
"What's going on?"
And you hear
yourself mumbling.
-你听见自己在咕哝：
-他妈的教皇，我并没错
Dogs fucked the Pope.
No fault of mine.
(MUMBLING)
Ether is the perfect drug
for Las Vegas.
对拉斯维加斯来说
情感催化剂是最好的毒品
ln this town
they love a drunk.
Fresh meat.
在这个地方，
他们喜欢鲜肉
Come on, buddy. Come on.
Holy. . .
快点，伙计，快点
So they put us
through the turnstiles
and turned us loose inside.
然后，他们就把我们推进了
十字转门，把我们丢到里面了
(DRUM ROLL)
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士们，先生们…
boys and girls,
男孩，女孩们…
visitors of all ages,
-各位朋友们…
the Bazooko Casino Circus
proudly presents,
-巴祖娱乐场马戏团
很自豪地推出节目…
the Flying Fellinis!
空中飞人
(WHOOPING)
Oh, my God !
上帝
(SNIFFS DEEPLY)
(SNARLING)
Fuck!
Excuse me.
对不起
Get out of my way, you. . .
不要挡着我的路，你--
(ELEPHANT TRUMPETS)
DUKE NARRATING: A drug person
can learn to cope
with things like
一个吸毒的人能应付这种事
比方说他看到了已故的姥姥…
seeing their dead grandmother
crawling up their leg
with a knife in her teeth,
爬上了他们的腿
她牙齿里还插着一把刀…
but nobody should be asked
to handle this trip.
但没有一个人能处理
我们这一次的行程
Bazooko Circus
is what the whole hep world
would be doing Saturday night
如果纳粹党赢了这场战争…
if the Nazis had won the War.
毫无疑问的，星期六晚上
这里就会是消遣的好地方
This was the Sixth Reich.
这就是第六帝国
Place your bets!
Where everyone's a winner
and nobody's a loser!
下赌注吧！
所有的人都是大赢家！
Step right up and shoot
the pasties off the nipples
of a 1 0-foot bull dyke
走近看看，来看看，
只把馅饼从十英尺高的
那个奶嘴上射下来…
and win a cotton candy goat!
就可以赢得棉花糖
(JABBERING)
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
Step up to this
fantastic machine!
来，走进这个奇妙的
机器里看看！
For just 99 cents,
your likeness will
appear 200 feet tall
只需要99分
你的两百英尺高的肖像…
on a screen over
downtown Las Vegas.
就能在拉斯维加斯市区的
一张大屏幕上出现
For just 99 cents more
you can have a voice message!
只要再多加99分
就可以留下你的声音信息！
随便你说什么都可以，伙计！
Say whatever you want,
fellow!
Oh, they'll hear you,
all right!
所有的人就都听到你的声音了！
你的肖像会有两百英尺高！
You'll be 200 feet tall !
DUKE NARRATING: The ether
was wearing off.
催化剂的作用开始减弱了
The acid was long gone.
迷幻药的效力早就退了
但是霉斯卡灵的作用
还是很强
But the mescaline
was running strong.
(MAN CHATTERING)
好的霉斯卡灵总是见效慢
Good mescaline comes on slow.
The first hour's all waiting.
在第一个小时里
它们的效力都潜伏着…
And then about
halfway through
its second hour,
然后开始慢慢地进入
第二个阶段…
you start cursing
the creep who burned you
because nothing's happening.
你开始咒诅那个烧伤你的人
因为什么事情都没有
And then, zang!
接下来…
我讨厌说这个
I hate to say this
but this place
is getting to me.
但这个地方已经
让我中邪了
(HICCUPPING)
I think I'm getting the fear.
我想我-
开始害怕了
Nonsense.
胡说.我们来这儿是
为了找美国梦的
We came here to find
the American Dream.
我们已经起步了
难不成你现在还想打退堂鼓？
Now that we're
right in the vortex,
you wanna quit?
You must realize, man,
we've found the main nerve.
你必须认识到，伙计
我们是无路可退的
That's what
gives me the fear.
所以-
我才开始害怕
Oh, look!
What?
-看！
-什么？
那儿，有两个女人在
在跟一个北极做爱
There's two women
fucking a polar bear.
Don't tell me
those things.
不要跟我说那些事情
Not now, man.
不要在现-
现在，伙计
This is my last drink.
我不想再喝了
你可以借给我多少钱？
How much money
can you lend me?
Not much. Why?
不多，你想干什么？
I have to go.
Go?
-我想走
-走？
Yeah. Leave the country.
-是的，离开这个鬼地方
-好的，现在平静下来
Oh, no. Calm down.
You'll be straight
in a few hours.
过一会儿，你就会站直了
不要再坐下去了
Just sit down.
Sit the fuck down.
Don't fuck around, man.
This is serious.
不要乱闹，这很重要，伙计
One more hour in this town,
I'll kill somebody.
让我在这里多待上一个小时
我肯定会杀人的
好吧，我借钱给你
Okay,
I'll lend you some money.
我们会好一些吗？
Come with me.
-我要马上离开这里
-好的
I wanna leave fast.
Okay.
Let's pay this bill,
get up very slowly.
买单
慢慢地站起来-
我想会有很长一段路要走的
I think it's gonna
be a long walk.
WOMAN: Light, sir?
火机，先生？
Do they pay you
to screw that bear?
他们雇用你跟-
那头熊干，是不是？
What?
什么？什么？
What the fuck
did he say to me?
He's drunk.
-他刚刚对我说了些什么？
-他喝多了
You'd better take care
of your friend.
你最好照顾好你的朋友
Madam, sir, baby, child,
whatever, can I pay?
女士，先生，婴儿，小孩，
随便什么东西吧，我可以付-
Here, take this.
That should be enough.
拿着
这也许够了
All right, come on.
Let's go downstairs
and gamble.
快下来
我们下楼去赌一把
You guys don't
fucking give up.
你们这些家伙是不会放弃的
Where'd he go?
他去哪了？
Where did he go?
他会在哪呢？
-这个东西什么时候才停下来？
-停下来？
When is this
thing gonna stop?
Stop?
Stop it!
It won't stop.
It's never gonna stop, man.
-让它停下来！
-它不会停下来的
永远都不会，伙计
Don't move. You'll fall down.
不要动，你会恢复知觉的
妈的，他--
Fuck, he's. . .
Where did he go? Oh.
他会去哪了-
Come on. Let go.
快点，我们走吧
Quick, like a bunny.
Hop! Hop!
快点起来，不要像个傻瓜似的
快点，跳下去
Come on. Hop!
I can't!
-快点，跳下去！
-妈的！
Oh, you sniveling,
chicken shit bastard !
Stop it!
你在哭
你这个胆小鬼
All right.
好的
快点-
妈的
Fuck!
Come on.
You fell, you fell. Let's go.
起来，你摔倒了，你摔倒了
我们走吧
Son of a bitch.
You pushed me.
杂种，你推我了
Go away!
Come on.
-走开！
-走吧
All right. You stay here
and go to jail. I'm leaving.
好吧，你就待在这等着
进监狱吧，我要走了
Come on, you fiend !
你这个魔王！
Step right over. . .
Nothing. I want nothing.
-走开-
-什么都不要，我什么都不要
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
Come on.
有个杂种在后面踢了我一脚
Some son of a bitch
just kicked me in the back.
Probably the bartender.
也许是酒吧间男招待吧
因为你对女服务生说了坏话
Wanted to stomp you
for what you said
to the waitress.
Holy moley! Holy moley!
Cows are gonna kill me!
-游戏，游戏
-鸡可以杀了我
Bisexuals are gonna kill me.
两性人也可以杀了我
Let's get out of here.
Where's the elevator?
我们出去
电梯在哪？
No, fuck! Don't go
near the elevator, man !
不要进电梯！
那是他们设下的陷阱
That's just what
they want us to do.
Trap us in a steel box,
take us down to the basement.
Come here.
把我们困在那个铁笼子里面
把我们带到地下室去
(GUN FIRING)
Don't run, man.
不要跑，伙计.
他们会找借口向我们开枪的
They'd like any excuse
to shoot us.
You drive. You drive.
你开车
I think there's
something wrong with me.
我好像有点问题
开错门了
Wrong door. Wrong door.
走错门了
DUKE NARRATING:
This is not a good town
for psychedelic drugs.
这个城市并不适合吸毒
Extremely menacing vibrations
were all around us.
四周都布满了陷阱
We finally made it
to the room,
我们总算找对了门
但是却打不开锁
but the key
wouldn't open the door.
Those bastards have changed
the lock on us, man.
-那些杂种换了我们的锁
-已经换了？
Already?
They probably
searched the room, man.
他们极有可能
搜了我们的屋子
Jesus Christ,
we're finished.
天，我们完了
Move out of the way.
Look out! Look out!
小心点，小心点
(GRUNTS)
(EXCLAIMS)
把所有的东西都上闩
Bolt everything !
Use all the chains!
把所有的铲子都找来
(MUMBLING)
这个主意不错，不错
That's better. That's better.
这一串是从哪来的？
Where did this one come from?
那是拉喀达的
That's Lacerda's.
Yeah. Yeah.
I thought we might need it.
我想，这对我们会有些用的
What for?
-干什么用？
So we can go up there
and blast him out of bed
这样的话，我们就可以
去他的地方，用一根灭火水龙带
把他炸到天上去
with a fire hose, man.
I think we should leave
that poor bastard alone.
我想我们最好不要去惹他
He told me he was
gonna turn in early, so. . .
-他跟我说过，他一般
睡得很早，所以--我知道
I knew it.
He got a hold
of my woman, man !
他抢走了我的女人，伙计
你是说那个娇小金发女
跟那个摄影师搞到一块了？
You mean that blonde groupie
with the film crew?
妈的，想他鸡奸她吗？
Shit.
Think he sodomized her?
That's right.
Laugh about it.
肯定会，他一定很得意
He's gluing her eyes
shut right now, man.
他们现在一定都睡着了
You goddamn honkies
are all the same.
你们这群白人都一个德性
你们这群白人都一个德性！
Jesus God Almighty, man,
where'd you get
that big fucker?
全能的主啊，伙计
你从哪搞来的那个东西？
Room service sent it up.
客房服务部送上来的
I needed something
to cut the limes, man.
我需要些东西来切雷姆，伙计
Limes? What limes?
雷姆？
什么雷姆？
They didn't have any.
他们这没有
雷姆是不会在沙漠里生长的
They don't grow
in the desert.
That dirty toad bastard.
那只可恶的赖蛤蟆
Should've taken him out
when I had a chance.
有机会一定要除掉他
(ROARS)
Now he has her, man !
他现在拥有她，老兄
He got a hold of my baby,
yeah.
是的，他抢走了我的女人
DUKE NARRATING:
l remembered the girl.
我还记得那个女人
We'd had a problem with her
in the elevator
a few hours earlier.
几个小时前，
我们在电梯里遇到那个女人
My attorney had
made a fool of himself.
我的律师完全是在自作多情
-我觉得你长得很像她
-你这样认为吗？
I think you look
just like him.
You think so?
You must be a rider.
Hmm?
你一定是个骑手
She's speaking to you.
她在跟你说话
你是第几个种类的？
What class are you in?
种类？
Class?
What the fuck do you mean?
说什么呢？
What do you ride?
你开的是什么车
See, we're here getting
a little footage
on the race for
我们这儿有少量的胶卷
准备为这场比赛-
拍点电视系列片
a television series.
我想，也许我们可以找你来拍
I thought maybe
we could use you.
找我？
我开的是一辆-
Oh, use me? I ride a. . .
"Mother of God," l thought.
Here it comes.
“圣母玛利亚'”要出问题了
I ride the big fuckers.
You know? Big ones.
我骑的是一辆大的
你知道吗？一辆大的
The really big fuckers. Yeah.
是一辆真真大的车
Vincent Black Shadow.
文森特.布莱克.雪多
We're with the factory team.
我们是工厂队的
Right.
Bullshit.
-瞎说
-什么？
What?
Bullshit.
瞎说
Hmm?
I think there's
some kind of ignorant,
我想这儿大概有个无知的
胆小的家伙-让开点，伙计
chicken shit. . .
Move over, man.
An ignorant chicken
fucker in this town.
一个无知的胆小的家伙在这
You pink motherfucker.
你这个红毛怪
I can show you
better than I can
tell you, ma'am.
要判断一个人，
就要看他做事的方式
Got a light?
有火机吗？
No.
没有
You don't trust me, do you?
Huh?
你不相信我，是吗
-不要那样子笑-好的，
我知道你们这些家伙的手段
Put the smile away.
It's okay.
I know these guys.
Keep trying me, jerk-off.
Keep trying me.
继续笑啊，不要摆出
这种怪像继续作弄我啊
You wanna impress her?
你想取宠于她？
用我来取宠于她
Well, impress her with me.
妈的
Oh, fuck.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(GONZO WHOOPS)
No, you goddamn freak! Freak!
不，你这该死的小丑
妈的
The police will be
coming after you.
警察追来了
(SINGING) For your Iove
把钥匙给我
Give me the key.
Give me the goddamn key!
钥匙给我
(SINGING) For your Iove
(WHOOPS)
l give you everything and more
不
Put the knife away.
-把刀放下
-我走了一整天了
I been walking all day.
Come on.
来吧，就在我的口袋里
It's in my pocket. Come on.
(SINGING) For your Iove
l give you everything
l give you diamonds
l know the place
that will excite
Goddamn it.
它妈的
It's serious now, man.
这很重要，伙计
That girl understood, man.
那个女孩明白了
Whew.
She fell in love with me, man.
她爱上我了，伙计
Eye contact, man.
那是眼神与眼神之间的默契
Wait.
等等
(GROANS)
I should go up there
and castrate that fucker.
我要上去把那个王八蛋
变成个太监我会负责任的
I'll take the blame, man.
Let's just leave that
weird fucker alone, man.
Come on.
我们不要去管那个家伙了吧，
伙计
你跟他妥协了吗？
Have you made
a deal with him?
Did you put him on to her?
Huh? Huh?
你想帮他抢走她吗？
Huh?
All right, look. . .
好的，听着…
You better put
that goddamn blade away, man.
你最好把刀放下
Get your fucking head
straight.
头脑清醒点
I'm gonna go get
the car washed.
我去洗车
当你跟毒贩子打了几年交道后
你能学到的一件事就是…
DUKE NARRATING:
One of the things you learn
after years of dealing
with drug people,
is that you can turn
your back on a person,
你可以不理睬一个普通人…
but never turn
your back on a drug.
但却不能不理睬一个毒…
Especially when it's waving
a razor-sharp hunting knife
in your eye.
特别是当他拿着一把
明晃晃的刀在你眼前晃时
(BELL DINGS)
(WOMAN SOBBING)
(SLOT MACHINE CLICKING)
What was l doing out here?
我来这儿是为了什么？
What was the meaning
of this trip?
这次旅行有什么意义？
Was l just roaming around
in a drug frenzy of some kind?
难道我就只是来这个
吸毒狂愤的人群中闲逛…
Or had l really come
out here to Las Vegas
to work on a story?
真的只是来
加斯维加斯做报道？
Who are these people,
these faces?
这都是些什么人？
Where do they come from?
他们从哪里来？
They look like caricatures
of used car dealers
from Dallas.
他们看起来就像是从漫画中
走出来的贩买二手车的商人…
And, sweet Jesus,
噢，亲近的上帝
他们中有些人
在星期天清晨4：30…
there are a hell
of a lot of them
at 4:30 on a Sunday morning,
still humping
the American Dream,
还在寻找美国梦-
that vision of the big winner
somehow emerging
在维加斯娱乐场这个
腐烂的地方，大赢家的灵光…
from the last-minute,
pre-dawn chaos
of a stale Vegas casino.
总是在黎明到来的
最后一刻来临
Twenty.
We change a 20.
-二十
-选二十
Thank you.
谢谢你
Here we go.
Okay.
-开始
-好的
(SINGING) Spinning the wheeI,
spinning the wheel,
spinning the wheel
转吧，转吧
Make me rich
Make me very rich
转出我的财运来
(EXCLAIMING)
That's 1 0.
-是十
-你这个杂种
Oh, you bastard !
-妈的
-对不起
Shit.
Sorry.
DUKE NARRATING: No, no.
Calm down.
不，不，冷静些
Learn to enjoy losing.
要学会承受失败
(HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING)
搞错没有，伙计，
这里发大洪水了吗
Fuck, man, it's the fucking
Great Deluge in here.
Don't touch that.
Leave it alone.
不要碰那个，不要碰
不要动它，伙计
Don't fuck with it, man !
Jesus Christ.
Oh, God.
上帝
你把这些这幻药都吃了吗？
Did you eat all this acid?
That's right. Music!
不错，音乐！
You better pray to God
there's some Thorazine
in that bag.
你最好向上帝祈祷
那些袋子里有氯丙秦
Otherwise, you're in
bad fucking trouble.
-否则，你要有大麻烦了
-音乐，伙计，放录音带
Music, man,
put that tape on !
What tape?
Jefferson Airplane.
White Rabbit.
-放什么录音带？
-杰弗逊飞机乐队.“”白兔''
I need a rising sound.
-声音大些
-你真是没药可救了
You're doomed.
我不过离开两个小时
I'm leaving here
in two hours.
Then they're gonna come up
here and beat the mortal shit
out of you
他们就来到这里
用浴盆里的精液
把你的命给夺走了
right there
in that fucking tub.
(GRUNTING)
All right, I'll do it!
I'll do it.
好的，我给你打开！
我给你放，给你放，伙计
I'll do it. Fuck, man.
Just do me one last favor,
will you?
可以帮我最后一个忙吗？
Give me two hours.
That's all I ask, man.
我只要你给我两个小时
让我在天亮前睡一会
Two hours to sleep
before tomorrow.
This is fixed.
-我怀疑…
It's gonna be
a very difficult day.
这会是个不寻常的一天
I'll give you all
the time you need.
不管你想要多少时间
我都可以给你
Electrocution.
We don't want that.
电死
我们可不想这种事发生
Fuck off.
滚蛋
(FARTS)
(SINGING) When Iogic
and proportion have fallen
Goddamn it!
它妈的
(SINGING) SIoppy dead
And the White Knight
is talking backwards
我来看看
Let's see.
(SINGING) And the Red Queen's
off with her head
Remember
噢，万能的主啊
Oh, God Almighty.
GONZO: Help! Help!
Help me! Help!
救命！救命！救命！救命！
-救命！-妈的，
他简直就是在自寻死路
Shit! He's killing himself!
(SINGING)
What the dormouse said
Don't touch it, man.
Don't touch it!
不要碰它，不要碰它
(GROANING)
For fuck's sake, man !
拜?！
(SINGING) Feed your head
(MUTTERING)
Back, God. . .
Back, motherfucker!
回去-
回去，他妈的！
(GASPING)
On a roll, man !
I need it again !
-摇滚！再放！
-什么？
What?
当它唱到那个奇异的音符…
When it comes to
that fantastic note,
(PANTING)
when the rabbit
bites its own head off.
当兔子咬掉它自己的脑袋时…
I want you to throw
that fucking radio
我就想让你把那个收音机…
into the tub with me.
扔到我的浴盆里来
Fuck, you've gone
completely sideways, man.
妈的，你简直疯了
That'll blast you
right through the wall.
它会把你爆出墙
不出十秒就让你死翘翘
You'll be stone dead
in 1 0 seconds.
Fuck, they'll make me
explain things. Shit.
-妈的，他们会抓我去问话的
-胡说
Bullshit.
Don't fuck with me now, man.
I am Ahab.
现在不要惹我，我是亚哈
上帝
Jesus Christ.
All right, you weird fucker!
Sit down ! Back in the tub!
好的，你这个小丑！
坐下！回到浴盆去！
I'll plunge this into
your fucking throat.
否则我让它直进你的喉管
Don't make me use this,
man.
不要逼我用这个
好吧，伙计
All right, man.
也许唯一的解决方法
Probably the only solution.
好的，让我想清楚点
Let me make sure
I've got this all lined up.
You want me to
你想让我…
throw this thing into the tub
when White Rabbit peaks,
is that it?
把这个丢到浴盆里去，当它唱到
“”白兔''顶峰时，是不是？
Oh, fuck.
妈的
I was beginning to think
I was gonna have to go outside
我想我最好还是到外面…
and get one of the
goddamn maids to do it.
去叫个服务员来做
Oh, no. I'll do it.
得了吧，我来做好了
Shit. What are friends for?
妈的，这大概就是朋友吧
(GROANING)
(SINGING) I think she'II know
你准备好了吗
You ready?
(SINGING) Where Iogic
Close your eyes.
闭上你的眼睛
(SINGING) And proportion
Yeah, good boy.
好的，乖孩子
(SINGING)
Have fallen sloppy dead
Rabbit! White Rabbit!
-兔子，白兔！-安静点，它妈的
你在浪费我的时间
Quiet, goddamn it!
You're wasting my time!
Higher, man. Higher.
出去！滚出去
(VOLUME INCREASES)
(SINGING) Remember
好的，闭上眼睛，十…
Okay, close those peepers.
Ten.
(GROANING)
What the dormouse said
Nine. 1 1 1 !
-九…一百一！
(SINGING) Feed your head
52!
五十二！
嗨，嗨
Feed your head
Hey! Hey! Hey!
嗨
我需要休息
(GONZO SHRIEKING)
You bastard !
你这个杂种
Mace! Mace, man.
You want this?
梅斯！梅斯，伙计
你想要这个吗？
You'd do that,
wouldn't you?
你不会这样做的，不是吗？
Well, why not?
-为什么不会？
-你这个杂种
You fucking bastard !
Hell, just a minute ago
you were asking me
to kill you.
几分钟前，你让我杀了你
现在你却想杀我
Now you wanna kill me.
不然你让我怎么做
去把警察叫来吗！
What l should do, goddamn it,
is call the fucking police!
Boy, are you upset.
你是不是晕头了
There'd be no point, man,
calling the cops.
不可以叫警察，没门
我别无选择
There's no choice.
谁敢跟你这个满脑子都
装着迷幻剂又四处游荡的人
睡在一起.
l wouldn't dare go to sleep
with you wandering around
with a head full of acid
wanting to slice me up
with that goddamn knife.
更何况，
你还要用刀把我割成肉片
谁说要把你割成肉片了？
Who said anything
about slicing you up, man?
I just wanted to cut
a little "Z" in your forehead.
我只是想在你的额头上
打个Z''形的印记
(WHEEZING LAUGHTER)
Get back in the tub.
回到浴盆去
吃些胺红让自己平静下来
Eat some reds
and try to calm down.
Smoke some grass.
Shoot some fucking smack.
吸一些大麻，白粉
Shit, man, do whatever
you gotta do, but please,
去吧，你愿意干什么
就去干什么吧…
l need some fucking rest, man.
Please. Please.
我需要休息
伙计，拜?你，拜?了
Get up, you pig fucker!
出去，你这头猪！
起来！起来！
Up! Up!
Well, I, uh. . .
我-
Yeah.
是的
You need to get to work.
你还有工作要做
Goddamn, what a bummer.
天，真是个无赖
You scurvy shyster bastard.
你这个奸诈之徒
我是新闻博士，伙计
l'm a Doctor of Journalism,
man.
Go on.
快走
Don't let me keep you up.
我不会输给你的
Now...
Don't let me keep you up.
我不会输给你的
Get in there
and clean your shorts!
你的短裤是干净的吗
Clean your shorts, goddamn it,
like a big boy. Go on!
去洗干净，妈的
要像个乖宝宝！快去！
Pig!
猪！
迷幻药已经在
他身体里发生了作用
DUKE NARRATING: The acid
had shifted gears on him.
The next phase
would probably be
接下来就该是
一些可怕的恶梦了
one of those
hellishly intense
introspective nightmares.
Must get some peace.
该有些宁静
DUKE NARRATING:
Four hours or so
of catatonic despair.
-大约会有四个小时左右的
紧张性精神失落症
Damn drugs.
-该死的毒品
Mmm?
lgnore the nightmare
in the bathroom.
我们就先不要谈
那浴室里的恶梦
Just another ugly refugee
from the love generation.
那只是人爱情
失意的另一个避难所
My attorney had
never been able
to accept the notion
我的律师从没就不能
接受这个观点…
often espoused by
former drug abusers
他总是受到以前
毒品观点的影响…
that you can get a lot higher
without drugs than with them.
没有毒品的话
人可以上升到一个更高的境界
And neither have l,
for that matter.
而我也是
(SINGING)
When the truth is found
To be lies
And all the joy
Within you dies
Don't you want
somebody to love
Don't you need
Wouldn't you love
somebody to love
You better find
Love
DUKE NARRATING: 1965.
The great San Francisco
acid wave.
1965.旧金山的毒品风波
(SINGING)
When the garden flowers
l recall one night
in a place called the Matrix.
我记起了一个叫
马特利克斯的地方，我在这-
There l was.
Mother of God. There l am.
圣母玛利亚！我在这
Holy fuck.
妈的
Clearly l was a victim
of the drug explosion,
很显然地，
我是毒品大爆炸的牺牲品…
a natural street freak just
eating whatever came by.
一条自然的“街道怪诞思想”
会吃掉所有路过的人
Does anybody want some LSD?
有人想要迷幻药吗？
我这儿有…
I got all the makings
right here!
现成的！
(ECHOING)
All I need is a place
to cook.
我只需要
找个地方加工一下
l decided to eat only
half of the acid at first.
我决定首先只
吃掉一半迷幻剂…
But l spilled the rest
on the sleeve of
my red woolen shirt.
然后把剩下的撒在
毛线衣的袖子上
出什么问题了？
(ECHOING)
What's the trouble?
我袖子上的…
(ECHOING) Well, all this
white stuff on my sleeve
这些白色物品…
是迷幻药
is LSD.
运气很糟…
DUKE: With a bit of luck,
his life was ruined forever.
从此他的生命就被毁了…
他常想在他酒吧那扇窄门后…
Always thinking that just
behind some narrow door
in all his favorite bars,
men in red woolen shirts
are getting incredible kicks
from things he'll never know.
穿着红色毛衣的人…
从他根本就不知道的东西
身上得到一种难以置信的乐趣
Strange memories
on this nervous night
in Las Vegas.
在拉斯维加斯度过的
这个紧张之夜，让我留下了
一种奇怪的记忆
Has it been five years? Six?
有五年？还是六年？
lt seems like a lifetime,
the kind of peak
that never comes again.
似乎有一辈子那么长
这种紧张再也没出现在我身上
(SINGING) Love is but a song
we're singing
San Francisco
in the middle '60s
六十年代中期，旧金山…
was a very special time
and place to be a part of,
那是个特殊的年代
特殊的地方…
but no explanation.
-但是没有任何一种解释…
(SINGING) We can make
the mountains ring
No mix of words
or music or memories
语言，音乐或者是记忆…
can touch
that sense of knowing
that you were there and alive
可以说得出你在
那里活过的那种感觉…
in that corner of time
in the world,
whatever it meant.
它只是这个世界上
一个时间的角落而矣
(SINGING)
Though the bird is on the wing
And you may not know why
那里，随时随地…
There was madness
in any direction,
at any hour.
都有着疯狂的举动
(SINGING) Come on peopIe, now
你可以在
任何一个地方游行示威
You could strike sparks
anywhere.
(SINGING)
Try to love one another
There was a fantastic
universal sense
那个时候流行着一种感觉…
that whatever we were doing
was right,
我们做的任何事情
都是对的
我们是赢家
that we were winning.
And that, l think,
was the handle.
我想，也许那也算是
一种人生的赌注吧
(SINGING) Some may come
and some may go
That sense of inevitable
victory over the forces
of old and evil.
那种不可避免的成功感
超越了一切邪恶的力量
跟军事是完全挂不上钩的-
我们根本就不需要那个
Not in any mean
or military sense,
we didn't need that.
Our energy would
simply prevail.
我们的敌人随时
都可能会强大起来
是的，我们那时动力十足
We had all the momentum.
We were riding the crest
of a high and beautiful wave.
我们正赶上了那次浪潮的高峰
所以现在，五年之后…
So now,
less than 5 years later,
you can go up a steep hill
in Las Vegas and look west
当你爬上拉斯维加斯
陡斜的小山坡向西望时…
and with the right kind
of eyes,
只要你用对角度…
you can almost see
the high-water mark,
就能望见高潮时期的那个标志…
that place where
the wave finally broke
and rolled back.
那个潮流涌来…
又激退的地方
(SINGING) Try to Iove
one another right now
(ELECTRIC PIANO PLAYING)
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
(SINGING) Want some whiskey
in your water?
Room service!
客房服务
Some sugar in your tea?
What's all these crazy
questions they're asking me?
Good morning, sir.
早上好，先生
This is the craziest party
there could ever be
What do you want, man?
What do you want?
你想干什么？
Room service.
Get out.
-客房服务
-出去
Mama told me not to come
你走错房间了，出去
You're not mine.
You're in the wrong room.
Get out! Get the fuck out!
I've got a gun.
It's not mine, really.
Get out.
我有把枪，但它不是我的，
我没骗你
The. . . The. . . The. . .
What?
-清单
-什么？
The bill.
All right.
Will you sign for it?
Yeah, I'll get it. Hurry up.
-你可以…在上面签个字吗？
-好的，快点
不要动
Don't move, man.
Be very still. There we go.
可以了
不许对任何人说
Say nothing to no one, man.
Open up the window
Let some air into this room
DUKE NARRATING:
The decision to flee
came suddenly.
突然有了种想逃的感觉，
也许不是
Or maybe not.
That cigarette you're smoking
about scared me half to death
也许是我一直
就在计划着要逃
Maybe l'd planned it
all along, subconsciously
waiting for the right moment.
只是在浅意识里一直
就在等这么一次机会
Mama told me not to come
我想，那张清单就是原因之一…
The bill was a factor,
l think,
because l had no money
to pay for it.
因为我没钱支付
Mama told me not to come
Our room service tabs
had been running
我们的客房服务是
每小时29到36元…
somewhere between
29 and 36 dollars per hour
是48小时服务
for 48 consecutive hours.
lncredible.
真是难以置信
That ain't the way
to have fun, son
How could it happen?
这怎么可能呢？
But by the time
l asked this question,
但是现在已经没人
能回答这个问题了
there was no one around
to answer it.
That rotten attorney of mine,
Dr. Gonzo, was gone.
我的那个死律师贡兹已经走了
He must have sensed trouble.
也许他早就知道会有麻烦了
Hmm? Oh. A "Z"?
一个“Z”？
惊慌
Panic.
它悄悄爬上我的脊梁骨
就像是吸过迷幻药后的颤抖
lt crept up my spine
like first-rising vibes
of an acid frenzy.
我开始接受这可怕的现实
All these horrible realities
began to dawn on me.
DUKE: Oh, fuck.
妈的
我在这儿…
DUKE NARRATING: Here I was,
alone in Las Vegas,
一个人孤苦伶仃的待在
拉斯维加斯，完全被毒品扭曲
completely twisted on drugs.
没有现金
也没有替报社找到新闻报道…
No cash,
no story for the magazine,
而最最重要的是
我没钱支付饭店的清单
and on top of everything else
l had a gigantic goddamn
hotel bill to deal with.
l didn't even know
who'd won the race.
Maybe nobody.
我甚至不知道
谁赢了那场比赛
也许没人赢
How would Horatio Alger
have handled this situation?
霍雷肖.阿尔杰
会如何处理这种情况？
Stay calm. Stay calm.
冷静，冷静
l'm a relatively
respectable citizen.
我是个有名望的公民
Multiple felon, perhaps,
but certainly not dangerous.
很坏，也许，
但是我并不是危险人物
计程车
Taxi !
Luckily, l had taken
the soap and grapefruit
很幸运，我很早就把肥皂
以及葡萄和其它一些行李
放进车里了
and other luggage
out to the car
a few hours earlier.
现在-
Now, it was only a matter
of slipping the noose.
是时候逃了
Hey! Here, take this.
All right.
嘿，拿着
-杜克先生，杜克先生！
-该死
Mr. Duke! Mr. Duke!
Oh, shit.
-我们一直在找你
-比赛开始了，他们都等着我呢
We've been looking for you.
The game was up.
They had me.
很多经典的书
都是在监狱写成的
Many fine books have been
written in prison, huh?
-先生？
-什么？
Sir?
What?
这是你的电报
This telegram came for you.
事实上，并不是给你的
是给一个叫汤普森的人
Actually, it's not for you.
It's for somebody named
Thompson.
但它上面也写了
由杜克先生转交''你-你-
But it says,
"Care of Raoul Duke."
Do you. . . Do you. . .
Does that mean anything?
-这是不是很重要呢？
-是的，是的，是很重要，谢谢你了
Yes, yes, it means a lot.
Thanks.
我们查了一下登记薄
Yeah, I checked the register
for this man Thompson.
We don't show him,
but I figured he might
be part of your team.
但没他的记录，所以我们猜想，
他应该跟你是一道的
He is. Don't worry.
I'll get it to him.
-是的，不错，我会
转交给他的-好的
Yeah. What confused us was
让我们有些困惑的是…
Dr. Gonzo's signature
on the telegram
from Los Angeles
贡兹博士的签名是从洛杉矶来的
但据我们所知，他人在这
when we knew he was
right here in the hotel.
Right.
You did the right thing.
是的，你们做的不错
报界信息你们是看不懂的
大部份时间，我们用的都是密码
Never try to understand
a press message.
About half the time,
we use codes.
Especially with Dr. Gonzo.
特别是跟贡兹先生，再见
See you.
Tell me. . .
请问一下
(TIRES SCREECHING)
博士什么时候醒？
When will the doctor
be awake?
-醒？你指的是什么？
Awake? What do you mean?
Well, my manager, Mr. Heem,
would like to meet him.
我们的经理黑姆先生
想见见他
也不是什么大不了的事-
It's nothing unusual,
Mr. Heem likes to meet
all of our large accounts,
黑姆先生只是个人有些…
put them on a personal basis,
you know?
想了解那些清单数目
比较大的客房，你明白吗？
Just a chat and a handshake.
只是认识一下，
聊聊，明白吗
You understand.
是的，但如果我是你…
Of course, but if I were you,
我会等他吃完早餐后
再去找他…
I would leave the
doctor alone until after
he's eaten his breakfast
because he's
a very crude man.
因为他脾气很坏
上帝
Jesus God !
No!
请等等
但也许，他过一会会有空吧？
But he will be available
maybe later this morning?
Look, the telegram is
actually all scrambled.
电报的事，我想跟你说清楚
事实上是汤普森写来的，
不是他
It's actually from Thompson,
not to him.
All right?
Now, I've got to go.
I've gotta get to the race.
懂了吗？好了，我得走了
我要去比赛场地
But there's no hurry.
The race is over.
-您不用急，比赛已经结束了
-对我来说还没有
Not for me.
Well, let's have lunch !
我们一起用午餐！
Righty-o, man. Righty-o.
好的，伙计，好的
天
(SINGING) Now, the bricks
lay on Grand Street
DUKE NARRATING: Jesus.
Bad waves of paranoia.
Madness. Fear and loathing.
这股偏执的，疯狂的，
让人恐惧而又嫌恶的潮流
lntolerable vibrations
in this place.
这股难以忍受的激动
马上从这个地方滚吧
Get out.
The weasels were closing in.
l could smell the ugly brutes.
已经接近黄鼠狼了
我可以闻到那股味
帮我最后一个忙，主
Do me one last favor, Lord.
先不要落下你的锤
再给我五个小时的时间
Just give me five more
high-speed hours
before You bring
the hammer down.
让我摆脱这辆车
离开这该死的沙漠
Just let me get rid
of this goddamn car
and off this horrible desert.
(SINGING) Oh, Mama
ls this really the end?
To be stuck inside of Mobile
该死的混球
Oh, you evil bastard.
With the Memphis blues again
这是你该尽职的地方
你必须照顾好我，主
This is Your work.
You better take care of me,
Lord.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
If You don't, You're gonna
have me on Your hands.
-要不然的话
我就得提前去见你了
Pull over!
-停下，停下
Hey!
Pull over!
Good morning. How are you?
早上好，你好吗？
好的，伙计，干得非常漂亮
All right, man.
Doing very well.
Few people understand
the psychology of dealing
with a highway traffic cop.
很少有人知道
如何去应付那些路警
Your normal speeder will panic
and immediately pull over
to the side.
一般，人们总是很害怕
马上就把车停下来
This is wrong. lt arouses
contempt in the cop heart.
这样做是很不明智的
这样的话，他就知道你好欺负
Make the bastard chase you.
He will follow.
让这个的家伙在后面追你
他会跟着来的
最高时速45英里/时
But he won't know what to
make of your blinker signal
that says you're
about to turn right.
但是他肯定想不透
你为何用信号灯告诉他
你要向右拐
This is to let him know
you're pulling off for
a proper place to talk.
这不过是让他知道
你想找个合适的地点跟他说话
lt'll take him
a moment to realize
他大概很快就会明白
一会儿他得转个180度的大弯
that he's about to make
a 1 80-degree turn, at speed.
But you will be ready for him.
Brace for the "G"s.
Fast heel-toe work.
但你得作好准备
开车得有技术
要有很灵活的刹车
及加速的功夫
COP: Shit! Shit!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SIREN WAILING)
Hi. How are you?
嘿，你好？
Just what in the hell
did you think
you were doing?
你知道自己在做什么吗？
I wanna know.
Let me see your license.
让我看看你的驾驶证
Oh, yeah, of course.
There you are.
当然可以，就在这
Oh, my gosh.
我的天
It's me.
不会有错
我可以看看这个？
May I please have that?
DUKE NARRATING:
l knew l was fucked.
我知道这下我惨了
See you have
two cases of beer,
a basket of grapefruit,
你有两箱啤酒
一篮葡萄…
一堆T恤和毛巾
日光灯
stack of T-shirts and towels,
light bulbs.
You realize what you did
when you drive like that?
-你知道这样开车有什么麻烦吗？
-是的，我知道，我违章了
Yeah, I know. I'm guilty.
I understand that.
我知道，这是违章的
但是我已经做过了
I knew it was a crime.
I did it anyway.
Shit, why argue?
I'm a fucking criminal.
那又怎么样呢？
我是违章了，看着我
Look at me.
你的看法很奇特
You have a strange attitude.
Maybe.
也许
You know, I have a feeling
you need to take a nap.
知道吧，我想你该休息一下
There's a rest area
just up ahead.
前面就有个休息的地方
I'd like you to
go up there, pull over
and get a few hours' sleep.
我希望你开车到那里后
停车去休息一会
That's not gonna help me.
那对我没什么大的帮助
I've been awake for too long,
three or four nights, maybe.
Can't even remember.
我知道也记不清有几个
晚上没睡了，也许三四个吧
I go to sleep now,
I'm dead for 20 hours.
是的，我现在得睡会了
我已经精疲力竭了
What are you carrying
two cases of soap for, son?
你为什么要带上两盒肥皂？
我有洁癖，
喜欢让自己干干净净的
I wanna stay clean.
不
No.
是这样的
Here's how it is.
What I put in my book,
as of noon,
我已作下登记…
is that I apprehended you
for driving too fast.
你开车太快
我建议你到下一个休息区
(HUMMING)
I advised you to proceed
to the next rest area. . . Stop!
站住
I advised you to proceed
to the next rest area, your
stated destination, right?
我建议你到下一个休息区-
你的下一个目的地？
And take a long nap.
好好休息一下
Do I make myself clear?
我说的够清楚了吧
Well, how far is Baker?
离贝克还有多远？
I was sort of hoping to,
I don't know,
stop there for lunch.
我想在那儿停下吃午餐
It's not my jurisdiction.
这个不关我的事
City limits end 2.2 miles
beyond the rest area.
在休息区开车不得
超过2.2英里
做得到吗？
Can you make it that far?
I'll try.
我会尽力的
I've been wanting to go
to Baker for a long time.
Yeah. Heard a lot about it.
很久以来我就想去贝克了
久仰大名
Excellent seafood.
那里的海味不错
You know, I'm thinking,
a guy with your kind of mind
ought to try the land-crab.
我想，像你这样的人…
应该去尝尝地蟹
Excellent seafood.
-很不错的海味
-地蟹
Land-crab.
All right. Why not?
好的，谢谢
Thanks for the tip.
谢谢你的小费
Look at me in the eyes.
看着我的眼睛
Everything all right?
有什么问题吗？
May I have a little kiss
before you go?
我可以在走之前吻你吗？
I'm very lonely here.
我在这儿很孤单
(SINGING) Oh, Mama
Can this really be the end?
DUKE NARRATING: I feIt raped.
The pig had done me
on all fronts.
我感觉自己受了侮辱
那只猪吻了我的脸
And now he was going off
to chuckle about it on
the west side of town,
他现在一定在曼哈顿
西区吃吃地笑…
waiting for me
to make a run for L.A.
等着我逃回洛杉矶
休息区
Why, yes, Officer.
是的，长官
我会好好利用休息区的
Of course l'll take advantage
of that rest area.
And l can't tell you how
grateful l am for this break
you wanna give me.
对于你给我的这段休息时间
我真不知道该怎么感谢才好
Get a grip, man.
好好把握自己，伙计
lf l boom straight for L.A.
he'll bust me for sure.
如果我直接回到洛杉矶
他肯定会逮捕我
No.
不，现在还不是时候摊牌
This was not the time
for a showdown.
This was Death Valley.
这是死谷
(GASPING)
DUKE: Oh, fuck!
见鬼
Sweet Jesus, it's him.
Oh, my God !
天，是他
上帝
(HUMMING)
(ENGINE STALLING)
Shit! Come on,
you fucking bastard.
见鬼！
快走，你这该死的机器
Oh, God. Oh, God. Oh, God.
I've got to go. I've got to. . .
上帝，上帝
我得走，我得走
他们抓住我了，他妈的
Well, they've nailed me,
goddamn it.
I'm trapped in
some stinking desert
crossroads called Baker.
这片讨厌的沙漠
我被困在一个叫贝克的十字路口
I don't have much time, man.
The fuckers are closing in.
我没有多少时间了
那群笨蛋快要来了
They'll hunt me down
like a fucking beast.
-他们会像野兽似的追捕我
-你是不是有点妄想狂
GONZO:
You sound a little paranoid.
I need a fucking lawyer
immediately!
马上给我派个律师
What are you doing in Baker?
Didn't you get my telegram?
你在贝克做什么？
收到我的电报没有？
What telegram,
you worthless bastard?
什么电报，
你这个一无是处的王八蛋？
I'll cripple your ass
for this.
You brainless scumbag,
you're supposed to be
in Vegas.
没大脑的人渣
你现在应该在维加斯才对
I rented a suite
at the Flamingo.
我在佛朗明哥饭店
为你预订好了房间
You're supposed to be
covering the National District
Attorney's conference.
你得去国家检查官
会场弄回一份报道
l made all the reservations.
Everything is arranged.
我把一切事情都安排好了
Now, what the fuck are you
doing out there in the
middle of the desert?
你现在在那个荒无人烟的
沙漠做什么呢？
Nothing. Never mind.
It's all a big joke.
没什么，不用担心
不过是个玩笑
I'm actually. . .
I'm poolside at the
Flamingo right now,
事实上，我现在就在
佛朗明哥饭店…
talking through a portable
phone some dwarf brought
out from the casino.
用一个侏儒从娱乐场所
拿出来的便携式电话跟你通话
Yeah,
I have total credit here.
是的，我在这儿很受人敬重
你最好不要到这个地方来
Don't come anywhere near
this place, you bastard.
外国人在这里是很不受欢迎的
Foreigners
aren't welcome here.
DUKE NARRATING:
Well, this is
how the world works.
这个世界就是这么奇妙
All energy flows
according to the whims
of the Great Magnet.
自有它自己的运转规律
What a fool l was to defy him.
跟它作对简直就是个傻瓜
l was going back to Vegas.
l had no choice.
我必须再回到维加斯
我别无选择
(GUN FIRING)
不要在内华达州赌博
l had to get rid of the Shark.
我要甩掉那个骗子
Too many people
might recognize it,
especially the Vegas police.
大多数人都应该认识到这一点
特别是维加斯的警察们
Luckily, my credit card
was still technically valid.
幸运的是，
我的信用卡还是有效的
Now this was
a superior machine.
现在的这个可是个
比较高级的机器
Ten grand worth
of gimmicks and
high-priced special effects.
它的利用价值已远远
超过租用它时的一万元
The rear windows leapt up
with a touch like
frogs in a dynamite pond.
它的后窗抬起时
感觉就像是池塘里的青蛙
仪表板上那些深奥的数字…
The dashboard was
full of esoteric lights
and dials and meters
that l would
never understand.
我是怎么都不会看得懂的
如果那群猪在维加斯开会…
lf the pigs were
gathering in Vegas,
欢迎来拉斯维加斯
参加国家检查官会议
l felt the drug culture
should be represented as well.
我感觉毒品文化也会来凑热闹
And there was a certain
bent appeal in the notion
of running a savage burn
这一定会在拉斯维加斯…
on one Las Vegas hotel,
一家旅馆里喧起一阵龙卷风…
and then just
wheeling across town
and checking into another.
然后再跨过另一个州
卷到另一个旅馆
Me and 1 ,000 ranking cops
from all over America.
我和美国的警察
就都有事做了
Why not move confidently
into their midst?
我应该充满信心地
走到他们中间去
Welcome to
the Flamingo Hotel, sir.
欢迎来到佛朗明哥饭店
(GRUNTING)
先生？
Sir?
Yeah, hi. Right. Okay.
好的，是，谢谢
(SINGING)
Let me stay in your arms
l'm addicted to your charms
You're getting to be
a habit with me
l used to think your love
was something that l
Could take
Or leave alone
我来的不是时候
DUKE NARRATING: My arrivaI
was badly timed.
(SINGING) But now I couIdn't
do without my supply
l need you for my own
为什么吸毒者不知道这些事实
这个是我们要用到的模型…
This here model is one
that we had to use
when we took on
them little peckerheads
down there at Kent State.
我们在肯特州雇用了
那些家伙时
And this baby here. . .
这里的这个孩子-
我是密歇根州警察局局长
I'm a police chief
from Michigan.
Look, fella,
I have explained to you.
听着，伙计，
我得跟你说说我的情况
I have this postcard
which says that I have
a reservation in this hotel.
这张明信片上说
我有这个饭店的预订房间
I'm very sorry, sir,
but you're on the late list.
很抱歉，先生
但是你订单来的太晚了
And so, your reservation
has been transferred to. . .
It's okay.
-所以就被转到…
-不要着急
. . .the Moonlight Motel
which is just out on
Paradise Boulevard.
到…月光汽车旅馆…
就在天堂林荫大道那边
We've already paid
for our goddamn room !
我们已经付过费用了
Well, it's actually a very
fine place of lodging,
那里的住房条件相当不错
从这里过16条街就可以了
and it's only
1 6 blocks from here.
It has a pool, sauna, steam.
那里有游泳池，
桑拿浴，蒸汽浴
你给我听清楚
你这个恶心的同性恋者！
You listen to me,
you filthy little faggot!
I want a manager down here,
now, now!
叫你们经理马上下来，马上！
Now, because I'm sick of
listening to your dog shit!
我讨厌再听到你的胡言乱语！
I am very sorry, sir.
我，非常抱歉，先生
Get off of me!
Get away from me!
-放开我，放开我！
-我去为你叫辆计程车？
Can I call you a cab?
Sure, and I'll call you
a cocksucker!
当然，我会叫你同性恋！
DUKE NARRATING: Of course,
l could hear what the
clerk was really saying.
是的，我很清楚地
听到那个服务生说
听着，你这个老不死的
Listen,
you fuzzy little shithead !
我一直在这里…
I've been fucked around
in my time
by a fairly good cross section
忍受着你这个…
of mean-tempered,
rule-crazy cops.
脾气暴躁，
有些疯狂的警察的胡闹…
And now, it's my turn.
现在…轮到我了
So fuck you, Officer.
I'm in charge.
去死吧，长官
我是主管
Hey, listen,
I really hate to interrupt,
抱歉，非常抱歉，打断你们…
但我得先解决我们的事
but I wonder if I could
just slide on through
and get out of your way.
The name is Duke. Raoul Duke.
我是杜克，我想我的律师
已经替我订好房间了
I think my attorney
made the reservations.
杜克
Duke, Raoul.
是的，先生
Certainly, sir.
My bags. . . My bags are
out there in that white
Cadillac convertible there.
我的行李就在外面那辆
白色的卡迪拉克敞蓬车里
Maybe somebody could
bring it to the room for me.
一会，可以让人替我送上去
Well, let me get
a quart of Wild Turkey,
好的，再给我来一瓶WildTurKey…
五分之二的巴卡第…
two-fifths of Bacardi,
some ice for the room,
and let's see. . .
-再给房间里送点冰块，
再想想--不要冲动！
You just calm down !
Shit, let's try
some lime chunks.
What do you think?
另外，来点酸橙
可以吧？
没问题
I say okay.
-你不用担心
-好的，冷静点
You don't worry
about a thing.
Now, calm down.
有什么事的话，尽管叫我-斯芬
You don't hesitate
to call me, Sven.
好的，斯芬
All right, Sven.
非常感谢
(WAILING)
Thank you very much.
You. . . You. . .
-你-你-
-我理解，我理解，我理解
I know, I know, I know.
It's hideous.
这种事真是很讨厌
但一切都会好起来的，你不错
You're gonna be fine, though.
You're doing well.
I'll see you later. Wait.
Don't touch it.
再见
等等，不要碰
Good night. Pardon me.
Bye, Sven.
晚安，请让让，再见，斯芬
(CRYING)
看看你都做了些什么，
你都做了些什么
Look what you did !
Goddamn you,
we wouldn't stay in this
hotel if you begged us!
妈的，现在就算你求我
我们也不住这家饭店了
(SINGING) Magic moments
When two hearts are caring
Magic moments
Memories we've been sharing
家，温馨的家
Home, sweet home. Whoa.
What kind of sick shit. . .
噢，这里真是太…
(LUCY GRUNTING)
Oh, shit!
妈的
(GRUNTING)
Shit. What the fuck?
妈的，这是怎么搞的？
住口，住口
Stop, stop, stop.
She's biting my leg off!
她快把我的腿咬断了
你这只该死的猪！
You degenerate pig. Please!
没办法
Can't be helped.
My fucking leg !
-我的腿！
-那是“”露西，天上的钻石''
That's "Lucy In The Sky
With Diamonds."
Lucy, be cool,
goddamn it.
露西，冷静点
Remember what happened
at the airport, okay?
Come on.
还记得在机场发生的事，
是吧？走开
(LUCY WHIMPERS)
No more of that, okay?
That's my client, Lucy.
不要再这样子了，行吧？
这是我的委?人
他是杜克先生，很有名的记者
That's Mr. Duke,
the famous journalist.
He's paying for this suite,
Lucy.
这间房是由他付费的
他跟我们是一样
He's on our side.
他喜欢艺术家
He loves artists.
露西为芭芭拉.史翠珊画肖像
Lucy paints portraits
of Barbra Streisand.
Right?
是吗？
我是照着电视上画的
I drew these from TV.
真的
Really.
She came all the way down. . .
她特意从-
What's the name
of that town?
Montana.
-那叫什么地方来着？
-蒙大纳
Montana.
Just to give these
portraits to Barbra.
蒙大纳.想把这张肖像给巴巴拉
We're going over to
the Americana tonight
to meet her backstage.
我们今晚打算去
阿美里卡纳巴，在后台见她
DUKE NARRATING: I desperateIy
needed peace, rest, sanctuary.
我现在极需要宁静，休息…
和避难所
我不能再忍受这个：
l hadn't counted on this,
finding my attorney on acid
我的律师吃了迷幻药
正在求爱
and locked into some kind
of preternatural courtship.
Well.
They must have brought
the car around by now.
他们一定把车开过来了
所以…
So why don't
为何不…
ou-yay and I-ay
o-gay and et-gay the
uff-stay out of the unk-tray.
Absolutely. Yeah.
好的，没问题
Let's get the stuff.
我们有点私人问题要谈
We'll be right back, Lucy.
马上就回来，露西
-来，吻一个？吻一下，就一下
-不
Give me a kiss?
One kiss, one kiss.
No.
LUCY: No.
GONZO: One kiss.
-不，不
-就一下，不行吗？
No.
Why not?
Okay.
好的
Don't answer the phone.
不要接电话
God bless.
上帝保佑你们
你想干什么？
Well, what are your plans?
干什么？
Plans?
The child in the bedroom.
-房里的那个孩子
-露西
Oh, Lucy.
I met her on the plane.
我是在飞机上遇到她的
Yeah.
She's a religious freak.
是的，她信教
I gave her a cap
before I realized. . .
我给了她点迷幻药-
Jesus, she's never even
had a drink.
天，后来才知道
她还从没喝过酒
好吧，也许这是个解决的方法
DUKE: Well,
it'll probably work out.
We can keep her loaded,
and then peddle her ass
at the drug convention.
我们让她先沉迷在药品里
然后把她放到毒品大会上去叫卖
Yeah,
she's perfect for this gig.
不错，她很适合做这个
These cops'll go
50 bucks a head
这些警察会50元买袋毒品
然后干她
to beat her into submission
and then gang-fuck her.
We can set her up
in one of these
backstreet motels,
我们可以在后街小巷里开一家店…
hang pictures of Jesus
all over the room,
在房间里挂满耶稣像
然后让她跟那群猪干
and then turn these
fucking pigs loose on her.
Hell, she's strong, man.
She'll hold her own.
她很健康
一定吃得消
天，我知道你很恶心…
Jesus Christ,
I knew you were sick,
but I never expected to
hear you actually say
that kind of stuff.
但我并不想从你的嘴里
说出这么脏的话来
You filthy bastard.
-你这个王八蛋，-从经济学上
来讲，她是上帝送来的礼物
Straight economics, man.
This girl's a godsend.
妈的，
她一天就可以让我们赚一千
Shit. She could make us
a grand a day.
That's ugly, man.
Stop talking like that.
好了，这真是太可耻了
不要再说种话
我想她一次
至少可以干四个人
Well, I figure she can do
about four at a time.
If we keep her full of acid,
that's more like two grand
a day, maybe three.
只要我们让她吃足迷幻药
我们一天可以赚两千或更多
住口，伙计
Hold on, man.
What if I just jump on you
and beat the dog shit
out of you?
我真该把你揍一顿
让你不要再说这些屁话？
Would that make
you feel any better,
you filthy bastard?
你认为，
这样子是不是更好呢？
All right, listen to me.
好的，听我说
In a few hours,
she'll probably be sane
enough to work herself
几个小时后，她马上就会
清醒过来…
into some sort of towering
Jesus-based rage
她会很模糊地记起…
at the hazy recollection
of being seduced by
some kind of cruel Samoan
一个很野蛮的萨摩亚人诱使她…
who fed her liquor and LSD,
喝酒吃迷幻药
把她带到维加斯一家旅馆…
dragged her
to a Vegas hotel room
and then savagely
penetrated every orifice
in her little body
然后用他那异教徒的方式…
with his throbbing,
uncircumcised member.
践踏她幼小的身躯
这真是太恶心了
(WOMAN GASPING)
That's so ugly, man.
Well, fuck, truth hurts.
That's "Argh !"
-妈的，这是事实
-那真是太恶心了！
Yeah.
Argh !
-是的
-恶心！那真是太恶心了
That's argh ! Argh !
-恶心！
-恶心？
That's argh !
Argh?
-恶心！
-恶心
I wanted to help her, man.
我只是想帮她，伙计
Well, you'll go straight
to the gas chamber
for this one.
你会为此直接走进毒气室的
Even if you manage
to beat that, they'll still
send you back to Nevada
就算你没这个本意
他们也会以诱奸罪…
for rape
and consensual sodomy.
送你回内华达州
No, she's gotta go.
不行，她必须走
Shit.
该死
It doesn't pay to
try to help somebody
these days, huh?
这年头，要想做好人真难
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Let's go.
我们走吧
Yeah. Americana Hotel?
I need a reservation.
阿美里卡纳巴旅馆吗？
我要订房
For my niece.
为我的…侄女
Look, I want her
treated very gently.
She's an artist and. . .
听着，好好招待她
她是个艺术家而且-
Fuck off.
滚开.她看起来有些紧张
She might seem
a trifle high-strung.
She's doing her
Masters' thesis on,
well, Barbra Streisand.
她主要是为…
巴巴拉画肖像
It's time to meet Barbra.
-该去见巴巴拉了
-姓什么？
Last name?
I'd rather not say.
My brother's in politics.
我看这个问题我不能回答
我哥是政治上的人，你们明白吗
Yeah, you understand.
DUKE NARRATING:
l felt like a Nazi,
but it had to be done.
我感觉自己像纳粹党
但是事情不得不这样
是的，是的，对，对
Yeah, yeah, righto.
Okay, yeah. Bye.
Yummy, yummy, yummy
l've got love in my tummy
And l feel like loving you
(HORN HONKING)
Love is such a sweet thing
Good enough to eat
And it's just
what l'm gonna do
DUKE NARRATING:
Lucy was a potentially fatal
millstone on both our necks.
露西注定了是我们
命运中的一块倒霉石
Hurry the fuck up!
-快点！
-我们别无选择…
There was absolutely no choice
but to cut her adrift...
-只能让她自生自灭…
-天，节省你自己的时间！
Jesus Christ. Take your time!
...and hope her memory
was fucked.
希望她不要记得什么才好
Here's an extra 1 0 bucks,
buddy.
多给你十元
要保证把她安全送到
Make sure
she gets there safely.
(IMPATIENT HUMMING)
好了，搞定
That's that.
Hey, man, take off slowly.
Don't attract attention.
伙计，慢些开车
不要吸引别人的注意
(HUMMING)
Yummy, yummy, yummy
l've got love in my tummy
我们找家海味餐馆
吃红鲑鱼
Let's find a good
seafood restaurant
and eat some red salmon.
I feel a powerful lust
for red salmon.
我现在非常想吃红鲑鱼
(GONZO RETCHING)
不行，伙计，我们要迟到了
Oh, no, man.
We're gonna be late.
We gotta go.
我们得快点走
Goddamn mescaline.
他妈的霉斯卡灵
Why the fuck can't they
make it a little less pure?
他们干嘛不渗点假？
我欢迎各位…
l welcome you to the third
National D.A.'s Convention
第三次全国D.A.会议…
on Narcotics and
Dangerous Drugs.
我们要讨论的主题
是有关毒品的
And now, without further ado,
好了，现在请大家安静…
the man who will define
this cancer eating
at the heart of America.
他会来为我们解释
吞食了美国人心灵的这种癌症…
Dr. L. Ron Bumquist.
兰.巴姆斯特博士
I saw these bastards
in Easy Rider, but I didn't
believe they were real.
我在逍遥骑士看到这些家伙
但我不敢相信他们是真的
Not like this, man,
not hundreds of them.
不像这样，伙计，
不是他们中这么多人
They're actually
pretty nice people
once you get to know them.
一旦你了解了这些人后
会发现他们很可爱
Know them?
I know these people
in my goddamn blood.
了解他们？
我简直太了解这群人了
Don't say that
word around here.
You'll get them excited.
不要在这里说这种话
否则会引起公愤的
You're right.
-说得对
-对我们来说最有效的方法就是…
The most efficient
way for us to do this
is for each one of us
我们在场的每个人…
to try and attempt
to imagine what it is like
都来尝方式着…
去想想那些毒瘾…
inside of the possessed
mind of the addict.
很深的人他们是怎么想的
Hmm?
For example, a dope fiend
比方说…
一个有毒瘾的人…
refers to the reefer butt
as a "roach"
会把大麻的烟蒂…
说成是“”蟑螂''…
because it resembles
a cockroach.
在因为…
它看起来像蟑螂
What the fuck are these
people talking about?
他们在说些什么东西？
You've got to be crazy on acid
to think a joint looks like
a goddamn cockroach.
这简直就让人发疯
把那种东西想成是只蟑螂
你们应该注意到了我把这四种…
...you will notice that
l have distinguished four...
大麻制品或者大麻烟的社会…
Four distinct states of being
in the cannabis
or marijuana society.
状态分得很清楚
They are cool, groovy,
他们是一流的，最佳状态…
hip and square.
忧郁的也是乏味的
很少的时候，如果-
SeIdom, if ever...
疯子，伙计，他真是疯了
Too crazy, man. Too crazy.
(GRUNTING)
We should get the hell out.
What a fucking nightmare.
他们会杀了你的
真是场恶梦
lf he figures out
what is happening
如果他能知道发生了什么…
then he can rise one notch
说可以说他…
and become hip.
变得忧郁
但是如果说他相信自己…
And then if he can
convince himself
to approve
of what is happening,
也知道自己在做些什么…
then he becomes groovy.
然后就可以说
他进入最佳状态了
最佳状态
Groovy.
And then, after that,
he can actually raise himself
然后，过了这一阶段
他还可以提升自己…
to the rank of cool.
让自己达到一流的阶段
He can become one of those
那么他就变成那种…
cool guys.
一流的人了
MAN: Dr. Bumquist.
博士
You think the anthropologist
Margaret Mead's
你认为人类学者玛格丽特，
米德晚年的那些奇怪行为…
strange behavior of late
是否可以解释为
她对大麻已经上瘾了呢？
could be explained
by a private marijuana
addiction?
问得好
Good question.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
我不敢肯定地说
l'm not really sure
l can answer that.
But what l can tell you, sir,
is if Margaret Mead,
at her age
但是我想告诉你的是
如果玛格丽特，米德…
在她的那种年纪…
smoked grass,
吸毒的话…
she'd have one hell of a trip.
她的旅程就会变得非常艰难
(ALL LAUGHING)
One more layer
of deviance to the woman.
女人总是多面性的动物
This is fuckin' bullshit.
废话
I'll be out in the casino.
我要去娱乐场了
Shut up, man. Go to hell !
从前面下去，伙计！
非常感谢，谢谢你们
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
-谢谢，谢谢你们的支持
-放映机
Thank you.
Thank you for having me.
MAN: Projector, please.
-请让让
-好的
Excuse me.
All right.
(MUSIC PLAYING ONSCREEN)
MALE NARRATOR:
Know your dope fiend.
有毒瘾的人
Your life may depend on it.
你的生命就耗在上面了
You will not be able
to see his eyes,
because of Tea Shades,
你并不会看到他的眼神
因为Tea-Shades…
but his knuckles will be white
from inner tension.
但是他的手指
会因为内心的激动而苍白
当他找不到强奸的对像时…
And his pants
will be crusted with semen
from constantly jacking off
when he can't find
a rape victim.
内裤就会满是精液
He will stagger and babble
when questioned.
受到质问时，
他们会神智不清，迷迷糊糊
(WOMAN MOANING)
他并不会怕你的证章
He will not respect
your badge.
The dope fiend fears nothing.
他们是无畏的
He will attack for no reason,
with any weapon
at his command
他会随手抓起身边
一些武器攻击人…
-包括你们的
-没公德
(BOTH MOANING)
including yours.
Cheers.
Beware. Any officer
apprehending
-注意：任何一个警察都可以…
-请让让
a suspected
marijuana addict...
Pardon me.
...should use all necessary
force immediately.
Sorry. Pardon me.
-对嫌疑犯采取一些
必要的措施-不好意思，让让
One stitch in time
on him will usually save nine
如果他能及时采取行动…
(ECHOING) on you.
就可以救你们-
GONZO: Oh, God. Oh, God.
上帝，上帝
该死，该死
Shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
噢，上帝
(PHONE RINGING)
(GONZO MOANING)
喂？
Yeah?
Yes, Mr. Duke, hello.
You have one message.
是杜克先生吗
有人留信息给你
Call Lucy. . .
给露西回电话
(GONZO RETCHING)
...at the Americana Hotel,
room 1 600.
-阿美里卡纳巴旅馆，1600号房
-该死
Oh, fuck.
喂？
(DIAL TONE)
Hello?
露西打电话来了
Lucy called.
(GONZO RETCHING)
什么？
(TOILET FLUSHING)
What?
Lucy called.
-露西打电话来了
-谁？
What?
Lucy called, man.
露西打电话来了
(PHONE RINGING)
Those two men in the dock,
they gave me the LSD
在被告席的那两个人
他们给我吃了迷幻药…
and they took me to the hotel.
他们把我带到旅馆
我不知道他们对我
做了些什么，但我记得…
l don't know
what they done to me,
but l remember
很恐怖
it was horrible.
他们给你吃了什么？
(DUKE GROANS)
They gave you what?
迷幻药
LSD.
阉割！
JUDGE: Castration!
全部阉割！
Double castration!
Where's my .357, man?
Who the fuck knows, man?
-我的357在哪？
-鬼知道？
(CAR HORN HONKING)
你不能把我一个人
丢在这蛇窖
You can't leave me alone
in this snake pit.
You bastard, what did you do
with my .357?
你这个杂种，
你对我的357做过什么手脚？
This room is in my name.
-这间房是用我的名字注册的
-恶棍
Well, tough titty.
Okay, goddamn it!
该死的
You're right.
你说的对
She's my problem.
I'll call her,
I'll get her off our backs.
麻烦是我引起来的，
我给她打电话，我会摆平她的
It's gone too fucking far.
-好的，伙计，不要做过头了
-好的，我会考虑的
Well, I'll take that
into consideration.
Relax.
Relax!
-放松点
-放松点！
Let me handle this.
我来处理这件事
Where are my shoes?
-我的鞋子呢？
-请接阿美里卡纳巴旅馆
The Americana Hotel.
What did you do
with my goddamn shoes?
-你把我的鞋子搞哪去了？
-请接1600号
Room 1 600, please.
As your attorney, I advise you
to take a hit out
of the little brown bottle
作为你的律师，
不要动我放在刮胡箱…
in my shaving kit.
里那个褐色的东西
You won't need much.
你用不上的
Just a tiny taste.
那不过是…小玩意儿
Let's have it.
Ah, there it is.
在那
What is this shit?
That stuff
-这是什么鬼东西？
-这个东西…
可以让纯霉斯卡灵
看起来像啤酒
makes pure mescaline
seem like ginger beer, man.
Adrenochrome.
-肾上腺素红肾上腺素红？
Adrenochrome? Hmm.
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello.
喂
Hi, Lucy. God bless.
嗨，露西，上帝保佑
Hmm?
Yeah, it's me.
是的，是我
Hell, no,
I taught the bastard a lesson
he'll never forget.
什么？不.
我已经教训过那个杂种了
What? No, not dead.
什么？不，没死
But he won't be bothering
anybody for a while.
但他现在
不会烦任何一个人了
Yeah, I left him out there.
是的，我让他出去了
I stomped him.
我揍了他一顿
拔光了他所有的牙
I pulled all his teeth out.
我记得想上帝…
DUKE NARRATING:
l remember thinking,
"Jesus.
"What a terrible thing
to lay on somebody
with a head full of acid."
让一个人吃那么多迷幻药
是多么可怕的一件事啊
But we have a problem.
但我们遇到麻烦了
That bastard cashed
a bad check downstairs
那个杂种欠下了一屁股债
而且把你也牵涉进去了
and gave you as a reference.
They'll be
looking for both of you.
他们会找你们俩麻烦的
Yeah, I know,
Lucy, but you can't
judge a book by its cover.
是的，，露西，但你总不能
根据书的封面来判断它的内容
Some people are
just basically rotten.
有些人真的是很渣
Anyway, the last thing
in the world you wanna do
不管怎么样，
以后你不要再往这里打电话了
is call this hotel again.
They'll trace the call,
put you straight behind bars.
他们会窃听这个电话
然后把你抓起来
(BABBLING)
No, I'm moving
to the Tropicana right away.
不，我会去热带天堂酒店
Hmm.
I'll use a different name.
I'll let you know what it is.
我会用个假名
到时候再告诉你
I gotta get off.
我要走了
Probably have this phone
tapped, baby.
也许这个电话有分机
Yeah, I know,
it was horrible,
but it's all over now.
-是的，我知道.这很恐怖
但现在一切都过去了
(BANGING)
Oh, my God.
There's someone at the door.
上帝，有人在敲门
(SQUEALING)
有人在敲门
(WHISPERING)
There's someone at the door.
(BANGING)
救世主
Christ! Hey!
No! I'm innocent!
It was Duke!
不，我是无辜的，那是杜克
It was Duke! Lucy! Lucy!
是杜克，露西，露西
I love you ! I love you !
(SCREAMING)
Don't put that thing on me!
不要把那东西放在我身上
(SCREAMING)
Whoo. Oh.
Well. . .
That's that.
搞定
(GURGLING)
你以后再也不会
听到她的声音了
That's the last we should
be hearing from Lucy, man.
(EXHALES)
She's probably
stuffing herself down
the incinerator about now.
她现在一定吓得要死
You know what we need?
你知道我们需要什么吗？
We need some opium.
我们需要一些鸦片
(GURGLING)
DUKE NARRATING: I remember
slumping on the bed.
我记得从床上掉下来了
His performance
had given me a bad jolt.
他的表演让我有些晕
For a moment, l thought
his mind had snapped,
那一刻，我以为这种想法
一下抓住了我…
that he actually believed
he was being attacked
by invisible enemies.
他真的相信他被一个
看不见的敌人攻击了
但房间很快又安静下来了
But the room was quiet again.
你从哪弄来这个的？
Where'd you get this?
不用紧张，
那可是真正的玩意儿
Never mind.
It's absolutely pure.
你最近在跟什么人鬼混？
What kind of monster client
have you hooked up
with this time?
Satanism freak.
恶魔
这种东西只可能有一个来源-
I think there's only
one source for this stuff,
the adrenaline gland
是从一个活人身上…
from a living human body.
的腺里弄到的
我知道，那个家伙
没有现金付给我
I know.
The guy didn't have
any cash to pay me.
He offered me human blood,
said it would take me higher
than I'd ever been in my life.
他给了我一些血，
说会让我进入到一种
从没体验过的境界里
我以为他在开玩笑
I thought
he was kidding.
Oh.
So I told him I'd just
as soon have an ounce
or so of pure adrenochrome.
所以我就跟他说
我要一些少量的肾上腺素红…
Or maybe just
a fresh adrenaline gland
或者是一些新鲜的肾上腺…
to chew on.
考虑考虑吧
DUKE NARRATING: I couId
already feel the stuff
working on me.
我可以感觉到它已经
在我身体里起作用了
The first wave felt
like a combination
of mescaline and methedrine.
每一阵感觉就像霉斯卡灵
和梅太德林的双重效力
Maybe l should take a swim,
l thought.
我想，也许我该去游泳
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
They nailed this guy
for child molesting.
他们逮捕了他
说他骚扰儿童
He swore he didn't do it.
他发誓说他没有做过
"Why should I fuck
with children?" he said.
"They're too small."
“我干嘛要骚扰儿童？''
他说”他们末免也太小了点''
(WHINING)
天，我还能说些什么？
Christ, what could I say?
Even a goddamn werewolf
is entitled to legal counsel.
像这样一种恶魔都有权力
请一个辨护律师
I didn't dare to
turn the creep down.
会不怕吗
他也许会拿起一把刀
然后剖开我的…
He might have
picked up a letter opener
and gone after my
pineal gland.
松果腺
You know?
Yeah.
-你知道吗？
-什么
Crazy.
Why not?
-太疯狂了
-有什么不可能的呢？
Shit. We should get
some of that.
发的，我们应该试试的
Just
就去…吃一些
看看会发生些什么
eat a big handful
and see what happens.
一些什么？
Some of what?
(GRUNTING)
(SNIFFING)
松果腺的精
Extract of pineal.
不错，是个好主意
Sure, that's a good idea.
One whiff of that stuff
will turn you
吸一口那种东西
就会让你入魔…
into something
out of a goddamn
medical encyclopedia, man.
进入到一种医学百科全书里
所没有的境界
好诱人的波波
Beautiful fucking tits.
伙计，你的头马上
就会肿大的像西瓜
Man, your head would swell up
like a watermelon.
You'd gain about
1 00 pounds in two hours.
-也许在两个小时内
就会有一百磅-不错！
Right!
长爪子，疣出血
Grow claws, bleeding warts.
是的
Yes.
然后你就会看到
有六个巨大的，多毛的波波…
And then you'd notice
about six huge, hairy tits
swelling up on your back.
在你后背长起来
真是太奇妙了
Fantastic!
你会瞎的
You'd go blind.
你的身体会肿起来
Your body would turn to wax.
他们会把你放到
一个手推车里
They'd have to put you
in a wheelbarrow.
当你求救时…
And when you scream for help,
你的声音就会像只浣熊
you'll sound like a raccoon.
(WHIMPERING)
Man, I'll try
just about anything,
伙计，我会试用所有的东西…
but I'd never in hell
touch a pineal gland.
但却决不会用这种松果腺
Finish the fucking story, man !
好了，闭嘴
What happened?
What about the glands?
出什么事了？
腺怎么了？
天，这个东西
已经让你达到高峰了？
Jesus, that stuff
got right on top of you,
didn't it?
看看你的脸，你快爆炸了
Look at your face.
You're about to explode.
Maybe you could just
也许你可以…
把我推到游泳池去
shove me into the pool.
Man, if I put you
in the pool right now,
如果我现在把你推进去的话
你就会像块石头似的沉下去
you'll sink
like a goddamn stone.
你吃得太多了
吃得太多了，太多了
You took too much, man.
You took too much. Too much.
(GURGLING)
Don't try and fight it.
不要试着反抗它
You'll get brain bubbles,
strokes, aneurysms.
不然，你的头会沸腾
会轰鸣，会有动脉瘤
你会枯萎而死
You'll just wither up
and die.
(DUKE MUTTERING INCOHERENTLY)
…继续杀害着无辜的人
MAN ON T.V. : They continue
killing innocent people!
Allowing the hopes
for peace and freedom
of millions of people
…让那些还抱有一丝渴望和平
和自由的数百万人民…
to be suffocated.
窒息而死
So tonight, to you,
所以今晚，给你…
the great silent majority...
最大的沉默-
Sacrifice. Sacrifice.
牺牲和牺牲…
(ECHOING) Sacrifice.
Sacrifice. Sacrifice.
牺牲和牺牲
牺牲和牺牲…
Sacrifice. Sacrifice.
牺牲和牺牲
Sacrifice.
WOMAN:
l feel the cottonwood
whispering above
Tammy, Tammy
(MOANING)
Tammy's in love
DUKE NARRATING: What kind
of rat-bastard psychotic
那个兔崽子，
神精病在此时此刻唱这种歌？
would play that song
right now, at this moment?
Tammy, Tammy
When l came to,
当我醒来时…
the general back-alley
ambience of the suite
was so rotten,
这间乱七八糟的房间里
到处是恶臭味…
一片狼藉
so incredibly foul.
How long had l been
lying there?
我在这儿躺了多久？
All these signs of violence.
所有的这一切
说明发生过一场暴力战
What had happened?
出了什么事？
(INSECT BUZZING)
There was evidence
in this room of excessive
consumption
从1544A.D.以来几乎
每一个吸毒的文明人都知道…
of almost every type of drug
known to civilized man
since 1 544 A.D.
这个房间里到处
都是过多消费的证据
(COUGHING)
Oh, ah, Debbie.
黛比
Thank God.
谢天谢地
Oh, Debbie. Hmm? Look.
黛比？看
DUKE NARRATING:
What kind of addict would
need all these coconut husks
什么样的毒瘾者需要这些
椰子茧衣和碎的香蜜瓜果皮？
and crushed honeydew rinds?
Would the presence of junkies
account for all these
uneaten French fries?
毒品商的帐单上是不是
都会有这些没吃的炸薯条？
These puddles of glazed
ketchup on the bureau?
这种泥浆似的调味番茄酱
在衣柜上？
Maybe so.
也许是吧…
But then why all this booze
但是为什么所有这些烈性酒…
and these crude
pornographic photos
和这些色情相片
都涂上了芥菜…
smeared with mustard
that had dried to a hard,
yellow crust?
那个干干的，硬硬的，
黄黄的应该是面包皮吧？
These were not
the hoofprints of your
normal God-fearing junkie.
那并不是
虔诚的有毒瘾者的脚
lt was too savage,
too aggressive.
这太野蛮了，太压抑了
GONZO: Put your hands
where I can see them.
-把你的手放在我看得见的地方
-什么？什么？
What? What?
Jesus God, man. Huh?
上帝，伙计？
Put your hands
where I can see them.
把你的手放在我看得见的地方
把你的手放在我看得见的地方！
Put your hands
where I can see them !
(GROANS)
DUKE NARRATING:
Grim memories
and bad flashbacks.
很残酷的记忆很糟的倒叙
Get a grip.
把握好自己
Maintain.
支持住
How many nights
and weird mornings
had this shit been going on?
还会有多少个
这样奇怪的日日夜夜啊？
(URINATING)
Something ugly had happened.
l was sure of it.
-一定发生了些不愉快的事
我敢肯定
(RETCHING)
Who is that?
Oh. Shit, that's me.
谁？该死，那是我
(MUTTERING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
-救命！
-出什么事了？
WOMAN: Help me!
The fuck!
What the fuck?
(GONZO YELLING)
见鬼
Oh, shit.
(WOMAN YELLING)
You're under arrest!
She must have
used a pass key.
-你被捕了！
-她一定是偷偷溜进来的
I was polishing my shoes
in the closet
我在壁橱里给我的鞋子打光
发现她偷偷溜进来
所以我就把她抓住了
when I noticed her
sneaking in, so I took her.
What made you do it?
Who paid you off?
-你为什么要这么做？
谁派你来的？-你们弄错了！
我是服务员！
Nobody! I'm the maid !
You're just as much
a part of it as they are.
-撒谎！你跟他们一定是一伙的
-哪个他们？
Part of what?
The goddamn dope ring.
那群贩毒团伙
你一定知道这间酒店的内情
You must know
what's going on
in this hotel.
Why do you think we're here?
你以为我们来这是做什么的？
(STUTTERING)
I know you're the cops,
我知道你们是警察了
但我以为你们是来参加大会的
but I thought
you were just here
for the convention.
I swear. All I wanted to do
was clean up the room.
我发誓.
我只是来打扫卫生的
I don't know
anything about no dope.
-我并不知道什么毒品团伙
-好的，小妞
Come on, baby.
Don't try to tell us
you never heard
of the Grange Gorman.
你肯定知道村庄格幔
I swear to Jesus
I never heard of that stuff.
我对天发誓，
我根本不知道有这种东西
Maybe she's telling the truth.
她说的也许是实话
可能不是他们一伙的
Maybe she's not part of it.
I swear I'm not. I swear.
我发誓，我不是的，
我发誓
In that case,
maybe she can help.
这样的话，
她也许会对我们有点帮助
Oh, yes,
I'll help you all you want.
是的，我随时乐意效劳
-我讨厌毒品
-我们也是
I hate dope.
So do we.
I think we should
put her on the payroll,
我想把她加到薪水册上
她可能帮得上我们
see what she comes up with.
You think
you can handle it?
What?
-你可以应付得了吗？
-什么？
One phone call every day.
每天一个电话
Don't worry
if it doesn't add up.
你不用担心这个
我们自会处理的
That's our problem.
You'd pay me for that?
你们给我付工资？
You're damn right we would.
说得不错
But the first time
that you say anything
about this to anybody
但是只要你对外人
说一句这里的事…
you will go straight to prison
for the rest of your life.
就准备后半生
待在监狱里去吧
What's your name?
-你呢什么？
-艾丽丝
Alice.
Prove it!
有什么证据
Okay.
-好的-只要给服务部
打个电话叫艾丽丝就行了
Just ring Linen Service
and ask for Alice.
All right, Alice.
好的，艾丽丝
You'll be contacted
by Inspector Rock,
Arthur Rock.
好的，探员罗克会跟你联系，
亚瑟.罗克
He'll be posing
as a politician,
他会以政治家的身份出现
你要装作不认识他
but you'll have no problem
recognizing him.
That's right, Inspector Rock
will pay you in cash.
罗克探员会付给你现金的…
$1 ,000 on the ninth
of every month.
-每个月的九号，一千元
-上帝！
Oh, Lord ! I'd do just about
anything for that.
我会为些赴汤蹈火
You and a lot
of other people.
-许多人都会这样做的
-到这边来
Come here. The password is,
"One hand washes the other."
暗号是：
一只手洗另一只手.''
The minute you hear that,
you say, "I fear nothing."
听到这句话，
你就说“”我所向无敌''
Say it.
-说一遍
-我所向无敌
I fear nothing.
Say it again !
-再说一遍！
-我所向无敌
I fear nothing !
Very good.
Get the fuck out of here.
出去吧？
是的，听着
Oh, yeah, listen.
Nice meeting you.
很高兴见到你
Don't bother
to make up the room.
你不用担心这里的卫生
Just leave a pile of towels
and soap outside the door
exactly at midnight.
只要每天午夜在门口
放上毛巾和肥皂就可以了
That way we won't
have to risk another
这样的，我们就不会
再遇上类似的情况了
one of these
little incidents, will we?
Whatever you say, gentlemen.
-听从吩咐，先生
-为上帝感谢正派的人
Thank God for decent people.
-再说一遍！
-我所向无敌！
DUKE ON TAPE: Say it again!
WOMAN: l fear nothing!
DUKE NARRATING:
Terrible gibberish.
胡说.残缺的记忆慢慢
从时间的烟雾中浮现出来
Splintered memories looming up
out of the time fog.
按下播放键
Just press play.
DUKE ON TAPE: This is it,
the American Dream.
这是，美国梦
Shit!
我们现在已经
没有后路可以退了
We're sitting
on the main nerve right now.
Yeah, don't get me started.
是的，我们现在不起身
The owner always wanted
to run away and join
the circus when he was a kid.
他小时候总想逃跑
然后进马戏团
Now the son of a bitch
owns the circus.
而他现在已经
拥有了整个戏团
Ah, man,
a real license to steal.
伙计，
那偷的可是张真正的执照
Oh, yeah.
美国梦已经成真了
The American Dream
come true, man.
Pure Horatio Alger.
纯洁的霍雷肖.阿格尔
Yeah. Welcome
to the happy place.
是的，欢迎来到幸福区域
(GRUNTING)
Listen, let's get down
to brass tacks here.
听着，我们该谈扑质问题了
How much for the ape?
猿多少钱？
MAN CHUCKLING:
How much you got?
你有多少钱？
DUKE ON TAPE:
How much do you think
you'd take for the ape?
你认为它值多少钱？
等等.我马上回来
Just wait here.
l'll be back.
DUKE NARRATING: Madness.
lt made no sense at all.
简直胡说八道
l desperately
needed the facts.
我迫切要知道真相
上帝！
小老人从窥镜里逃脱了！
(DUKE YELLING)
(HARD ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING ON TAPE)
出什么事了？
What the fuck is going on?
Where's the ape, man?
Where's the ape?
猿呢，伙计？
猿哪去了？
MAN: Forget about it.
He attacked an old man.
不要和它了
它正在攻击一个老人
Bit off the head
of the bartender,
它把酒吧男招待的脑袋给咬了
然后警察来了把它带走了
then the cops came
and took him away.
(GRUNTING)
Is that your car?
那是你的车吗？
(SHOUTING)
-保金多少？我要那只猿
-动物园太多了！
Somebody stop them !
-必须要有人阻止他们！
-你这个蠢瓜是不会理解的
DUKE: You poor fools
don't understand, do you?
This car is property
of the World Bank.
That money goes to Italy.
那辆车是世界银行的财产
钱在意大利
You can't put on a circus
without a tent.
没有帐蓬，你无法表演杂技
The top
is completely jammed.
You're right.
-上面是夹伤的
-不错
发动机出了问题
There's something wrong
with the motor.
We're all riders of the storm.
我们都是弄潮儿
Where are you,
you fucking monkey?
You can't do that!
-你在哪，王八蛋？
-你不能那样做！
全能的主！
你的子民选了休伯特.汉弗莱…
You people voted
for Hubert Humphrey.
And you killed Jesus.
你杀死了耶稣
DUKE: There was every reason
to believe that we'd been
heading for trouble,
任何一种迹像
都表明我们会有麻烦了…
that we'd pushed
our luck a bit too far.
我们的运气是糟透了
Oh, gosh, shit! God !
上帝
Right. Uh. . .
是的-
The possibility
心理和身理…
of physical
and mental collapse
毁灭的可能性…
is now very real.
现在已经很真实了
No sympathy for the devil.
没人会同情恶魔
Keep that in mind.
记住这点
Uh, buy the ticket. . .
买票…
Uh, take the ride.
开车
(WEEPING)
Hey, there.
你们好，
你们想买点吗啡吗？
You folks want to
buy some heroin?
(GONZO WEEPING)
Hey, honkies! Goddamn it!
嘿，白人！妈的！
Pull ahead, will you?
开快点
I want to sell you
some pure fucking scag !
我想买给你们
一些纯正的海洛因
Cheap! The real stuff.
很便宜的，是正品
I just got back from Vietnam.
不错，我刚从越南回来
Scag.
海洛因
I want to sell you
some pure fucking scag.
我要买给你们
一些纯正的海洛因
Shit! Fuck!
真正的家伙
听我说，你们这群混蛋！
把车停下，否则我杀了你们
Now hear me, you bastard !
Pull over! I'll kill you !
MAN ON TAPE:
Pull over! Come on!
停下，快点停下
Oh, shit. Oh, oh.
该死
(SLOW JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay. Let's see here.
好的，我们用这个来试试
DUKE NARRATING:
The mentality of Las Vegas
is so grossly atavistic
拉斯维加斯人的心理状态
有些返祖现像…
that a really massive crime
often slips by unrecognized.
那是一个还没有
被意识到的犯罪
North Vegas is where
you go when you've fucked up
once too often on the Strip.
当你上脱衣舞台时
北拉斯维加斯就是你去的地方…
And when you're not
even welcome in the cut-rate
downtown places.
如果像那种下三乱的地方
都不欢迎你的话
(SCREAMING)
The North Star Coffee Lounge
seemed like a fairly
safe haven from our storms.
北极星休闲咖啡室
看起来就像是我们的避风港了
No hassles, no talk.
没有激战，没有说话声
Just a place to rest
and regroup.
只是一个卸下武装
休精养神的地方
l wasn't even hungry.
我并不是很饿
There was nothing
in the atmosphere
of the North Star
在北极星，我不用把自己
武装起来，那里的气氛很融洽
to put me on my guard.
Two glasses
of ice water with ice.
两杯加冰的冰水
两杯
Two.
她看起来就像是简.拉塞尔
手笔下一幅损坏的漫画
She looked like
a burnt-out caricature
of Jane Russell.
She was definitely
in charge here.
很显然地，
她就是这里的老板
He did it very casually,
他只是随意地那样做了…
but l knew that our peace
was about to be shattered.
但是我知道
我们的宁静就要完蛋了
What was that?
那是什么？
What is this?
这是什么？
-是餐巾
-不要跟我讲那种废话
It's a napkin.
Don't give me
that bullshit.
I know what that means,
you fat goddamn pimp bastard !
我知道你说的是什么意思
你这个肥拉皮条的杂种！
That's the name of a horse
I used to own, ma'am.
我曾有匹马叫这个名
What's wrong with you?
-你怎么了？
-显然这个问题是火上浇油
秘密美人
DUKE NARRATING:
The question mark
was emphasized.
听着，你这个王八蛋
WAITRESS: You listen to me,
you son of a bitch.
I gotta take a lot of shit
in this place,
我这里接待过很多人
但不接待你这种美藉皮条客
but I don't have to
take it off no spic pimp!
Anybody that knows
anything knows that.
任何人都会这么想
好了！
付完帐就马上给我滚出去
Go on ! Pay your check
and get out of here!
想让我叫警察吗？
我会叫-
You want me to call the cops?
I'll call the fuck. . .
Oh, shit.
妈的
DUKE: Fuck.
该死的
你想叫警察？
Want me to call the cops?
(COUGHS)
柠檬蛋白排多少钱？
How much is that
lemon meringue pie?
从她的眼神可以看出她很害怕
但是她的大脑还没有失灵…
DUKE NARRATING: Her eyes
were turgid with fear,
but her brain was functioning
on some basic
motor survival level.
-还有点意识
-35分
35 cents.
-柠檬蛋白排多少钱？
-35分
How much is that
lemon meringue pie?
35 cents.
Whoo! What a waste of talent.
真是个天才，只可惜浪费掉了
No, honey,
I mean the whole pie.
不，亲爱的，我是说整份排
The whole pie.
整份排
(GASPS)
Hmm?
What, three?
什么，三？
(SNIFFLING)
Three? Four?
三？四？
Five? Hmm?
五？
这叫五
Five.
I'll be in the car.
我去车上等你
The sight of the blade
had triggered bad memories.
刀片钩起了不愉快的回忆
The glazed look in her eyes
said her throat had been cut.
她的眼神说明
她的喉咙被割断了
She was still in the grip
of paralysis when we left.
我们离开后
她仍然没恢复神智
(CAR ENGINE REVVING)
(SOBBING)
DUKE NARRATING:
lt was all over now.
现在一切都结束了
We'd abused every rule
that Vegas lived by.
我们破坏了维加斯的
每一条生活原则
烧了附近的小酒店
辱骂观光者，恐吓佣工
Threatening the locals,
abusing the tourists,
terrifying the help.
现在唯一的机会，
我觉得…
The only chance now, l felt
was the possibility
that we'd gone to such excess
就是这种可能性
我们可以做成这件事…
that nobody in the position
to bring the hammer
down on us
任何一个想定锤的人…
could possibly believe it.
都不可能相信这点
Fifteen minutes to get
my attorney to the airport,
十五分钟内，
我要送我的律师去机场
我们做得到吗？
could we make it?
Christ!
天！
No!
不，见鬼
Oh, fuck!
-该死
-妈的，妈的
Fuck.
Whoa, shit! Whoa, shit!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
You son of a bitch !
上帝，你这个王八蛋！
Oh, God.
上帝
(SCREAMING)
-你走错路了
-滚开，肥子
GONZO: You're going
the wrong way.
DUKE: The next left.
GONZO: Stop!
Go! Fuck!
停下，你这个该死的
Take a right here.
就在这下
小心开车，马上回来
GONZO: Goddamn it. We're lost.
妈的，我们迷路了
我们在这条凄凉的路上做什么？
What are we doing
out here on this
godforsaken road?
飞机场在那边
The airport's over there.
快，在那边
Goddamn it! It's over there.
我从没错过飞机
I've never
missed a plane yet.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
冲过去！
Hold on !
All right. I'm gonna drop you
right next to the plane.
好的，我把你送到飞机边上下
Fuck you. I'm gonna
have to take the blame.
They'll crucify me.
妈的，我会为些负责任的
他们会把我钉在十字架上
Right here, right here.
-就在这边，就在这边
-真可笑，伙计
Ridiculous, man.
Just say you were hitchhiking
to the airport,
and I picked you up.
你就说你是来搭飞机的
我是来接你的
-你这个杂种
-出去
You bastard.
Get out.
Hey, hey! Hey, listen.
-嘿，嘿！
-嘿，听着
不要听那些猪胡说
Don't take any guff
from these swine.
If you have
any trouble, remember,
如果你遇到了麻烦，记住：
you can always send a telegram
to the right people.
把电报拍给你想给的人
Yeah, explaining my position.
是的，解释一下我的立场
曾经有人为那个写过一首诗
Some asshole wrote
a poem about that once.
Probably good advice,
if you have shit for brains.
如果有什么问题的话
记得找些好的建议
(GONZO LAUGHING)
他走了…
DUKE NARRATING: There he goes.
One of God's own prototypes.
一个上帝的样板
A high-powered mutant
of some kind
像这样高智慧的种类
是不会大量繁衍的
never even considered
for mass production.
Too weird to live,
太奇怪了难以生存，
太稀少了难以死亡
(GRUNTING)
and too rare to die.
(SINGING) There you stood
on the edge of your feather
Expecting to fly
现在，我们所有的人
都在一条幸存的旅游线上
DUKE NARRATING:
We're all wired
into a survival trip now.
No more of the speed
that fueled the '60s.
没有60年代那般疯狂了
That was the fatal flaw
in Tim Leary's trip.
那是一条
提姆.李尔的旅游线
He crashed
around America, selling
"consciousness expansion"
他附落在美国
宣传“意识扩大化'”…
without ever giving a thought
甚至都不去想想
这个严酷的现实世界…
to the grim
meat-hook realities
that were lying in wait
for all those people
who took him seriously.
它一直在等着那些
把它看得很认真的人
All those pathetically
eager acid freaks
所有好些稀奇古怪的
可怜的吸毒者…
who thought they could
buy peace and understanding
for three bucks a hit.
他们以为他们只要花五元
买毒品就可以得到宁静和理解
But their loss and failure
但是他们的迷茫和失败…
is ours too.
也同样是我们的
What Leary took down with him
was the central illusion
of a whole lifestyle
李尔他记下的不过是
是他创造的…
that he helped create.
一个生活方式的幻想
A generation
of permanent cripples,
这一代他们是永久的跛子…
failed seekers,
他们探求失败…
who never understood
the essential old-mystic
fallacy of the acid culture.
他们永远都不会理解
这个古老神秘的毒品文化的本质：
The desperate assumption
这种绝望的设想
有些人…
that somebody
or at least some force
或者至少有某些力量…
is tending the light
at the end of the tunnel.
在这条隧道的心头看管着灯火
小心开车，马上回来
There was only one road
back to L.A.
为上唯一
一条能返回洛杉矶的公路
U.S. lnterstate 1 5.
美国州际15号道
Just a flat out
high-speed burn through
Baker and Barstow and Berdoo.
当你以高速疲惫不堪地
穿过贝克，巴斯托和帕多后
Then onto
the Hollywood Freeway,
就上了好莱坞高速公路
就陷入了一种狂乱的意识中…
straight into
frantic oblivion,
safety, obscurity.
安全，偏僻
Just another freak
in the freak kingdom.
只是另外一种奇怪的东西…
在这片奇怪的王国领土下
(SINGING) I was born
in a cross-fire hurricane
But l howled at my ma
in the driving rain
But it's all right now
ln fact, it's a gas
But it's all right
l'm Jumpin' Jack Flash.
lt's a gas, gas, gas.
l was raised by a toothless,
bearded hag
l was schooled with a strap
right across my back
But it's all right now
ln fact, it's a gas
But it's all right
l'm Jumpin' Jack Flash.
lt's a gas, gas, gas
l was drowned
l was washed up
and left for dead
l fell down to my feet
And l saw they bled
Yeah, yeah
l frowned
At the crumbs
of a crust of bread
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
l was crowned
With a spike
right through my head
Yeah, yeah, yeah
But it's all right now
ln fact, it's a gas
But it's all right
l'm Jumpin' Jack Flash.
lt's a gas, gas, gas
Jumpin' Jack Flash.
lt's a gas
lt's a gas.
(SINGING) Bright Iight city
gonna set my soul
lt's gonna set my soul on fire
l got a whole lotta money
that's a-ready to burn
So get those stakes up high
There's a thousand
pretty women waitin' out there
They're all waitin'
The devil may care
And l'm just a devil
with love to spare
So Viva Las Vegas
Viva Las Vegas
How l wish that
there were more
Than the 24 hours in the day
Even if l ran out of sleep
Boy, l wouldn't
sleep a minute away
Oh, there's blackjack
and poker
and the roulette wheel
A fortune won and lost
on every deal
All you need's a strong heart
and nerves of steel
So Viva Las Vegas
Viva Las Vegas
where the neon signs
are flashing
And the one-armed
bandits crashing
All those hopes
down the drain
Viva Las Vegas
turning day into nighttime
Turning night into daytime
lf you see it once
you'll never be the same again
l gotta keep on runnin'
Gonna have me some fun
lf it costs me
my very last dime
lf l wind up broke
then l'll always remember
That l had a swingin' time
Oh, l'm gonna give it
everything l've got
Lady Luck's with me,
Dice, stay hot
Got coke up my nose
to dry away the snot
So Viva Las Vegas
Viva Las Vegas
Viva, Viva
Las Vegas
Whee!